新浪微博@摆渡字幕组 译制
关注微博 掌握最新字幕资源
字幕组翻译/APP开发志愿者 招募中 报名QQ群：377256405
翻译：应非凡/Trouble、/jasmine/rise/决明子/Cecilia
翻译：百事的可乐瓶/♬Time Witness✟/mine香草
翻译：Margaret/say no/赤也小可爱是天使没错了!!
校对：JayJayLiu/Trouble、
你是哪位?
Who are you?
我他妈是你的噩梦 还问我是哪位
I'm your worst fucking nightmare, that's who I am.
我在跟你说话! 就是我!
I'm talking to you! That's who!
啥? 我管他娘的!
What? I don't give a damn!
你这是在侵犯小企业老板最神圣的基本权利
You're violating the most basic and sacred rights of a small-business owner.
你要知道和你斗争的是一个手无寸铁的年轻人
We're talking about a kid who doesn't have the means to fight you.
你下地狱吧 狗娘养的
gonna bury you, you motherfucker.
你在威胁我吗?
You threatening me?
有种当面说
Hey, do it to my face.
拿笔记下 我就在斯普林街75号 8楼
You got a pen? We're at 75 Spring Street, eighth floor.
来一趟呗 我们批准你来
Come on by. We validate.
参议员 我也很高兴和您谈话
Good talking to you, too, Senator.
-嘿  -干嘛?
- Hey. Hey. - What? Hey.
-我在跟你讲话 听着点  -好的
- Hey, I'm talking to you. - Yeah.
呃...
Uh...
我是理查德
I'm Richard.
很抱歉 我刚刚在听
sorry I was listeni
我不是故意冒犯您 我不是那样的人
I didn't mean to be rude. I wasn't raised like that.
你每句话都要以"我"这个字开头吗?
You always start every sentence with "I"?
我...
I'm...
我很抱歉 先生 我是新来的...
I'm sorry, sir. I'm the new...
我在供给室工作
I'm the supply room clerk.
你在偷听我讲话?
Eavesdropping on me?
先生 我没有
No, sir.
那好 你给我拿点胶带 我要用
Well, good. I need some more tape, so get on that.
嗯 关于胶带
Yeah, about that.
您可以在下面第二层抽屉找找
You're gonna want to check the second drawer down, sir.
里面有胶带和一盒新笔
Tape and a new box of pens.
我发现您的东西不够了
I saw you were running low.
啥不够?
What's that?
您可以看一下再下面一层的抽屉
You might want to check the next drawer down.
最底下那个
The one on the bottom.
你怎么知道我喜欢吃士力架?
How'd you know I like Snickers?
我猜你喜欢吃
I knew you liked them
因为我看到你垃圾桶里有它的包装袋
'cause I saw you had the wrappers in your trash can.
不要翻我的垃圾
Don't go in my trash.
没人动我的垃圾 你叫什么名字?
Nobody goes in my trash. What's your name?
理查德·朱维尔
Richard Jewell.
从今天起 我就叫你雷达了
From now on, I'm gonna call you Radar.
就像《陆军野战医院》里那样的?
Like from M*A*S*H?
出去
Get out.
和你在这玩的人看着都挺吓人啊
Pretty tough crowd you're running with here.
搞得我进来都有点紧张
Got a little nervous coming in.
先生 您还好吗?
How you doing, sir?
别担心 我经常来这
Don't worry, all right I come here often.
哇噢 打得不错嘛 雷达
Ooh. Nice shooting, Radar.
谢谢您
Thank you.
其实我是在为未来去执法部门做训练
This is actually kind of like practice for my future in law enforcement
比如亚特兰大警察局 联邦调查局 特工处也有可能
APD, FBI, maybe Secret Service.
你为啥想到那种地方工作?
What the hell'd you wanna do that for?
先生 因为我想保护人民安全
'Cause I believe in protecting people, sir.
我每天晚上都在学刑法
I study the penal code every night.
真是伴你度过寂寞长夜的好东西
Sounds like a humdinger of a night.
-好极了!  哦
- Yes! - Oh.
的确不赖 新手的好运气
Yeah, it's not bad. You got some beginner's luck.
9700分很高啊 好吧？
Yeah, what's wrong with 9,700?
第一次玩真的很不错了
nothing's wrong with for a first time.
第一次? 行吧 咱再来一盘
First time? All right, come on, let's go.
我只有30分钟午餐休息时间 我马上就得回去了
They only give me 30 minutes for lunch. I got to head back in a minute.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你就说和我在一起
You can say you're with me.
玩吧
Let's get it on.
开枪
Oh, shoot. All right.
-准备好了没?  -准备好了
- You ready? - Yes, sir.
看看你有多大本事 高手
Let's see what you got, hotshot.
我认真起来了啊
Yeah, I mean business, too.
-嗯哼?  - 你用单手打过没?
- Yeah? - You ever do it with one hand?
布莱恩特先生?
Mr. Bryant?
吓我一跳
Oh, Jesus Christ.
抱歉
Sorry.
我现在有点忙 你来的不是时候
Uh, I'm a little busy. Not... Not a good time, so...
-我明白...  - 待会再说?
- Yeah... - Talk later?
我知道你在忙
I know you're busy.
我只是想过来告诉你
I just wanted to come by to let you know,
我...我以后不在这里工作了
I... I'm not gonna be working here anymore.
所以来和你告别
Came to say bye.
我找到一个做安保的新工作
Got a new job doing security.
-不错  -明天就开始上班
- Okay. - So, that starts tomorrow.
好的 认识你很开心
All right. Hey, good to see you.
走之前 我想给你个东西
I wanted to give you something before I leave.
只是表达我的谢意
Just to say thank you.
好的
Hey, okay,
谢谢你
Thank you.
我注意到你又不够了
I noticed you were running low.
好的吧
All right.
嘿 过来
Hey, come here.
-干嘛?  - 你钱够吗?
- What? - You got enough money?
应该够的吧 为啥问这个?
Yeah, I guess so. Why do you ask?
这个作为 quid pro quo 你知道是什么意思吧？
This comes with a quid pro quo. You know what that is?
先生 我知道 Quid pro quo是拉丁语 意思是“等价交换”
Yes, sir. Quid pro quo is Latin. Uh, "This for that."
没错 这就是一个quid pro quo
That's right Well, this comes with a quid pro quo.
公平交易 我想和你做个约定
Fair exchange. So, here's the deal.
你当上警察时 我知道你一定会当上的
When you get your badge and I can see that day's coming,
不要变成一个混蛋
don't become an asshole.
懂?
You got me?
先生 我不会变成一个混蛋
No, sir, I won't become an asshole.
理查德啊 一点点权力就可以把人变成魔鬼
A little power can turn a person into a monster, Richard.
你可别成那样
Don't do that
明白吗?
Do you understand?
好的 呃...
Yeah. Um...
好的 我赚到第一笔薪水就还给您
Yeah, I'm gonna get that back to you the first paycheck I get, sir.
连本带利
I'm gonna pay you back with interest.
行 就这么定了
Okay. You do that.
谢谢您 布莱恩特先生
Thank you, Mr. Bryant
她说她踢过足球 我就说...
She said that she played soccer. So I was like...
"你是想让我用一只脚平衡啤酒瓶吗?"
"You want me to balance a tricking beer on my foot?"
天 你个大笨蛋
God, you dumbass.
我这忙着呢 你去开门
I got flustered. Get the door.
等一下
Wait.
不错嘛 高手
Nice try, hotshot
是那个保安
It's that rent-a-cop.
妈的
Shit.
开门
Open the door.
有何事 警官?
Yes, officer?
有人投诉噪音 所以来看看怎么回事
I heard a little noise complaint. Thought I'd come take a look around.
你得先有搜查令
You're gonna need a search warrant first.
小鬼 把你的手拿开
Son, you're gonna have to take your hands off me.
我只是随便看看
I'm just taking a little look-see.
首先 你根本就不是一个真警察
You're not even a real cop, first of all,
而且你没有搜查令 无权查房
and you're not allowed to search a room without a warrant.
-小鬼!  - 我们付租金的
- Boy! - We pay rent. We pay rent.
这是我们的住所 懂吗
It's like we live here, man.
这是我的工作
Boy, this is my job.
你必须得让我做我的工作
I'm gonna have to have you let me do my job.
-但这是我们的房间  -没错
- And this is our room. - Yeah.
你懂不懂什么叫非法搜查和查封
Are you aware of the notion of unlawful search and seizure?
混蛋 你可不能就这么大摇大摆走进来
Asshole, you're not supposed to just walk in here.
你继续说 考验我
Keep pushing me. Keep testing me.
-到时候有你好看  -是吗？
- See if you like where it gets you. - Yeah?
你没事吧?
You all right?
新生入学周我怎么说的?
What did I say freshman orientation week?
我说“校园里禁止喝酒”
I said, "No drinking on my campus.“
我不知道为啥没人让我注意到你之前的履历
I don't know why no one called my attention to your file before.
你看看 都是对你的投诉
I mean, all these complaints about you.
殴打学生
Physically assaulting a student.
还有 你真的在高速上把人拦截下吗?
And have you really been pulling people over on the highway?
呃 是的 先生 我有过
Um, yes, sir, I have.
我认为如果你在路上做酒精测试
I figured that if you do the drunk tests on the road,
校园里就不会发生事端
trouble never gets to the campus.
我们无权管辖高速公路
We don't have any jurisdiction on the highway.
我知道
And I realize that,
先生 但是我坚守法律与秩序
but I believe in law and order, sir.
-这是一国之本  - 嗯
- You can't have a country without it - Mmm.
你被哈伯沙姆县治安办公室开除了
And you were dismissed from the Habersham County Sheriffs Office.
“我不想在校园里出现违法乱纪的事”
"I don't want any Mickey-Mousing on these grounds."
这难道不是你说过的话?
Isn't that what you said?
我什么时候说过?
When did I say that?
我想你是在去年校庆日上说的
You said it at Founders' Day last year, I believe.
你正在喝酒 我朝你走过去
You were by the punch bowl. I walked up to you,
然后你和我说 额...
and you said to me, uh...
好吧 我打断了你
Well, I had interrupted you.
对此我向您道歉 我向您介绍了自己
I apologized, I introduced myself
然后我说 我将会是你雇佣过的最好的校园保安
and I said I was gonna be the greatest campus security guard you ever had.
然后你说 “不错
And you said, "That's good.
我可不想在这个校园里看到任何违法乱纪的事儿 ”
I don't want any Mickey-Mousing on this campus.
我想我应该还把它写下来了
I think I mighfve even wrote it down.
大部分事情我都会记录
I write down most things.
我会记下重点 应该在…
Try to keep the important one, and I believe…
在这 “我不想在这个校园里看到任何违法乱纪的事儿”
Oh yes, sir. “I don’t wanna any Micky-Mousing on this ground.”
这话是你说的 我只是秉公照办
Those are your words, sir, so… I took it seriously.
所以我想问问 你要如何处置宿舍的那些学生
And my question for you is, what about these kids in the dormitory?
喝酒等违纪行为 你要作何打算
Drink and all that. What are you gonna do about that?
要对他们进行严惩吗
We’re just going to let them slam?
你是主动辞职 还是我来开除你？
Do you wanna resign? Or would it be better if I fired you?
我被叫进办公室 还以为会有好事呢
So, I’m going into this guy’s office, and I think he’s bringing me into this.
我还以为他要嘉奖我或者给我升职
He’s gonna… you know, give me some commendation or promotion or something.
没想到他叫我去就是为了开除我
Don’t know to found out he brought me in there to fire me.
你敢信？
Can you believe that?
那本来就是个烂工作
Well, it’s a shit job anyway .
只有一群校园小鬼
college brats.
那么你接下来几个月又要在别处做安保工作？
So, you’ll just gonna be somewhere do security work next couple months?
我很尽职尽责的 只是那群孩子很难对付
I worked hard at that job. Those kids are just ran and won.
奥运会快到了 兄弟 你可以去保卫世界
Olympics is coming, brother. You can police the whole damn world.
庆典将在世纪公园举行
Celebration is at the Centennial Park.
这破城市终于有点重头戏了
Something finally happens in this stupid city.
我还要去听肯尼·罗杰斯的演唱会
and I get a fucking Kenny Rogers concert.
这就不错啦 还可能是马术呢
It could be worse. Could be equestrian.
-我得去隆胸了 -隆胸在这儿可没啥用
- I'm getting my tits done. - I don't see how that applies here.
明年这个时候 我们就都得在电视上抢工作了
This time next year, we're all gonna be scrambling for jobs on TV.
隆到D杯你觉得怎么样？
What do you think, D cup?
我会想你的 凯西 但我不觉得他们也会
I'd miss you, Kathy, but I don't think they would.
各位女士 我很抱歉我报道的混蛋杀人犯们
Ladies, I'm sorry my hot-ass murders
让你们写的那些无聊的屁话下了头版
keep knocking your boring bullshit off the front page.
我太抱歉了
I'm so sorry.
你想喝一杯吗
You wanna get a drink?
不了 我会拖你后腿的
I'd just slow you down.
随你便
Suit yourself.
行吧 如果你觉得这样最好的话
Yeah, if you think that's the best thing.
好
Great.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我得去世纪公园了
I get to go to Centennial Park.
沃森
Watson.
哎
Yeah.
我们的墨粉和复印纸都没了
We're out of toner and copy paper.
嗯...
Um...
好吧
Okay.
如果我去买 你就得接电话
If I go, you'll have to answer the phones.
不 我去买吧
No, I'll go.
商场里打折 打九折
There's a sale at the mall. It's 10% off
只要你能说出任何一个美国奥运健儿的名字
if you name anyone from the US Olympic team.
哦 真不错
Oh, joy.
我知道 人们得笑着过十六天
I know. People smiling for 16 days.
对你来说就是地狱
going to be awful for you.
不 这是个好事儿 对美国有线新闻网来说
No, it's gonna be wonderful for CNN,
对可口可乐公司和有停车位的人来说 都是好事儿
Coca-Cola, and anybody with a parking lot.
我真不敢相信 你真的做到了
I can't believe it. It's really here.
是啊 妈妈
Yeah, this is it, Mama.
如果我在奥运会这个工作表现的好 说不定又能当上警察
I do this Olympics gig well, maybe someone might make me a cop again.
几天后
He, in a few days,
他就会努力成为赢得奥运会的第一人...
will try to become the first man to ever win Olympic...
是啊 你尽力而为就好
Yeah, you just do the best you can.
嘿 我想着等你做完手术我再搬出去
Hey, I might not move out until after you've had your surgery.
你可能需要我帮你 怎么样？
You might need me for something. What do you think?
哦 你先去上班吧
Oh, you go on now.
等奥运会结束了再说这事儿 有的是时间
We got plenty of time to tend to that after the games are over.
开车过去要注意 别使劲嚯嚯车
No heavy foot of yours driving there. No heavy foot.
不会的 知道啦 妈妈
No heavy foot Yes, ma'am.
知道为什么吗？
And why is that?
因为如果车的保险涨了你会杀了我？
Because you'll kill me if the insurance goes up?
没错 我会杀了你
That's right I'd have to kill you.
你得杀了我
You'd have to kill me.
嘿 额...
Hey, uh...
我还是执法人员 对吧？即使我只是
It's still law enforcement, ain't it? Even if I'm just
负责看守一堆立体声设备什么的
watching over a bunch of stereo equipment and whatnot?
当然啦
Heck yeah.
你还是对抗坏人的好人啊 不是吗
You're still the good guy ing off the bad guys, aren't you
一会儿见 妈妈
I'll see you later, Mother.
去公园溜溜吧 你自己会无聊的
Come on down to the park, you get bored with yourself.
玩的开心啊
Have fun.
默罕默德.阿里 奥运会选手 就像年轻的卡修斯.克莱一样
Muhammad Ali, of course an Olympian, as young Cassius Clay,
是1960年罗马奥运会的拳击金牌获得者
gold medal boxer, 1960, the Games of Rome,
真是历史一刻
What a moment
1996年亚特兰大百年奥运会开幕式
The opening of the 1996 Centennial Olympic Games in Atlanta,
在温暖的夏季傍晚 在不知开往何处的火车上
On a warm summer's eve On a train bound for nowhere
遇见了一个赌徒 我们都累的睡不着觉
/ met up with the gambler We were both too tired to sleep
所以我们轮流
So we took turns a-starin'
望着窗外的黑暗
Out the window at the darkness
无聊侵袭 他开始讲话
The boredom overtook us And he began to speak
我把酒瓶递给他 他把我最后一口酒喝完
So I handed him my bottle And he drank down my last swallow
放哪儿都可以 谢啦兄弟
Anywhere's fine. Thanks, man.
没事儿
Yeah.
别客气
No trouble.
-你们还需要什么其他的吗？ -不了 谢谢
- You guys need anything else? - No, thanks.
需要什么就叫我一声
Vail guys need anything, give me a holler.
你得知道 什么时候坚持
You got to know When to hold 'em
什么时候放弃
Know when to fold 'em
什么时候一走了之 什么时候逃之夭夭
Know when to walk away, know when to run
绝不能数钱
You never count your money
当你坐在赌桌旁的时候
When you're sittin'at the table
赌完后 我们有的是时间算
There'll be time enough forcountin' When the dealin's done
-你离的很近啊 -是啊 我知道
- You're up close and personal. - Yeah, I know.
你看见他了吗？他就在那儿
You see him? He's right there.
我不敢相信那竟然是肯尼.罗杰斯！
I can't believe it's Kenny Rogers!
知道什么时候放弃
Know when to fold 'em
什么时候一走了之 什么时候逃之夭夭
Know when to walk away And know when to run
当你坐在赌桌旁边 绝对不能数钱
You never count your money When you're sittin'at the table
有的是时间数
There'll be time enough forcountin'
嗨 汤姆
Hey, Tom.
当你赌完的时候
When the dealin's done
啧啧啧 你好啊 凯西
Well, well, well. Hello, Kathy.
欢迎来到世界上最开心的地方
Welcome to the happiest place on earth.
真是个噩梦
Fucking nightmare.
知道哪儿有什么违法犯罪的事儿吗？
Isn't there anything crime-y going on anywhere?
我上哪儿知道去？我在这儿
How would I know? I'm here.
天啊
Christ.
想跳舞吗？
You wanna dance?
我倒是想 但我正在上班
I'd love to, but I am on duty.
哦 去他妈的上班 来吧
Oh, fuck duty. Come on.
没事儿的
Might as well.
打扰了 女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
-你需要水吗？ -嗯？
- You need some water? - Huh?
唔 水 今晚很热
Uh, water. It's a warm night
你就在这儿把水给出去吗？
Are you just giving them away?
是啊 我把水放在这里给警察们喝
Yeah, I keep them in here for police officers,
或者给怀孕的女士
or when I see a pregnant woman,
-是啊
-Yeah.
-祝你有个愉快的晚上  -你也是
- You have a good night - You, too.
好的
All right.
你得知道 什么时候坚持 什么时候放弃
You got to know when to hold 'em Know when to fold 'em
什么时候一走了之 什么时候逃之夭夭
Know when to walk away And know when to run
借过 抱歉
Excuse me, sorry.
这些运动员们都在抱怨
You got all these athletes complaining about
交通不好让他们迟到
getting to the venues late on account of the traffic.
但警察呢？我们不也哪儿都去不了吗
But what about the cops? We can't get anywhere, either.
昨晚我都想鸣笛了
I had half a mind to run my siren last night
就为了去趟超市
just to get to the supermarket.
-是啊 -太他妈挤了
- Mmm-hmm. - So damn crowded.
城市规划太差劲了
It's just poor planning by the city.
没一个人知道交通规划应该怎么办
There ain't a one of them jake-legs got a damn clue about traffic patterns.
-是啊 -你怎么想 理查德？
- Yeah. - What do you think, Richard?
觉不觉得市政府里全是没用的废物？
Think the city's a bunch of jake-legs?
我不知道 我觉得 你也知道
I don't know. I think, you know,
想要调节好这一切很难
it's hard coordinating all this and MARTA and all that
我很高兴我不用做这个
I'm glad I don't have to do it.
得了吧
Come on.
怎么了？
What?
很难的 做这些后勤工作
It's tough, doing all the logistics
还得确保一切都井井有条
and getting everything right.
看见那个梳马尾辫的男的了吗？
You see that guy over there with the ponytail?
你不觉得他的背包可疑吗？
Does his backpack look funny to you?
怎么可疑？
Funny how?
我现在看不见他了 我一会回来 各位
Now, I'm losing him now. I'll be back, guys.
打扰一下 先生？
Excuse me, sir?
嘿 哥们儿 来罐可乐
Hey, man, how about a cola?
嘿 兄弟 谢谢
Hey, brother, thanks.
干杯 哥们儿
Cheers, dude.
美国万岁！美国！美国！
USA! USA! USA!
棒！
Yes!
天啊
Jesus Christ.
你忘记转身了
You forgot the turn.
-行啦 这么严肃干嘛啊 兄弟？ -这他妈什么啊？
- come on, why so grim, big guy? - What the fuck is this?
-因为我觉得无聊 这很无聊 -我们都无聊
- Because I'm bored. It's boring. - We're all bored.
他们可不无聊
These guys aren't bored.
这舞蹈可真不是开玩笑啊 哈？
This dance is a real thing, huh?
我只是觉得我这样的人应该做比这更好的事儿 知道吗？
I just feel like I was made for something better, you know, than this?
是吗 你觉得我不是？
Yeah, you think I wasn't?
为了有更多时间去思考
To have a little more time to reflect
我现在在写一本书 不是关于我自己的
I'm writing a book right now, not about myself...
天啊 他的确挺帅的
My, my, he sure is handsome.
你确定不要三明治或者其它东西？
You sure you don't want a sandwich or anything?
不 妈妈 我觉得肚子不太舒服
No, Mama, I'm not feeling well. It's my stomach.
是吃什么吃坏了么？
Something you ate?
是吧 我猜是
Yeah, I guess so.
我一整个早晨都在厕所
I was in the bathroom all morning
你为什么要吃垃圾快餐食品？
Why you eat that fast food junk?
怎么了 理查德？
What is wrong, Richard?
我只是看着这个地方觉得
I just look around this place and I just think
这个世界欠你一个更好的  妈妈
the world owes you better than this, Mama.
这个世界欠咱们俩的
Shoot, the world owes us both.
但我们的生活就是这样
This is what we got
快去做你的工作 儿子
Go do your job, son.
哦 天呐
Oh, God.
好吧 这就去
Okay, now.
呦 亚特兰大！
Yo, Atlanta!
感觉怎么样
How you feeling
你们觉得一切都好么？ 说“是的！”
You feeling all right? Say, "Yeah!"
听着
Listen.
我知道一个地方
I know a place
没有人哭
Ain't nobody cryin'
这可能是件好事
This could be a good thing.
这怎么能是件好事呢？
How's this a good thing?
我们可以带你去跳水馆
We could bring you out to the diving venue.
让你“放”出一首国歌
We could have you fart the national anthem,
别让我现在笑
Do not make me laugh right now.
你怎么不跟别人换班?然后回家
Why don't you switch shifts with someone? Go home.
这是我最爱的乐队
This is my favorite band.
杰克.马克是你最爱的乐队？
Jack Mack is your favorite band?
我不会走的 我很好
I'm not leaving. I'm fine.
好吧
All right.
我去趟厕所
I'll be right back.
去吧
Go.
哇哦！
Whoo-hoo!
-看呀妈妈 我是克里.斯特鲁格  -再来一遍
- Look, Mom, I'm Kerri Strug. - Do that again.
很好
Nice.
你是谁？
Who are you?
爸爸  看着  我是米奇.盖洛德
Dad, look, I'm Mitch Gaylord.
太棒了
That's awesome.
快走 我们去买冰淇凌吃
Come on, let's go get some ice cream.
-好  -好了孩子们 体操时间结束了
- Yeah. - Okay, guys, enough gymnastics.
没有人哭
Ain't nobody cryin'
没有人担心
Ain't nobody worried
没有笑脸
Ain't no smilin' faces
没有 没有 没有
No, no, no
对种族说谎
Lyin' to the races
来吧 对种族说谎
Come on, now Lyin' to the races
现在对种族撒谎
say now Lyin' to the races
不好意思
Excuse me.
你们最好停手
Vail better stop what you're doing.
立刻
Right now.
怎么了 主管大人
What's going on, lard and in charge?
这个傻家伙！
This fucking guy!
你要干什么 取消我的电话服务？
Yeah, what are you gonna do, cancel my phone service?
没错 实话跟你说吧 小子
Yeah, let me tell you something, hotshot.
警察可不会这么客气的跟你说话
The police, they're not gonna ask you as nicely.
他们一看到酒鬼和混乱
They see the drunk and disorderly,
就会把你们铐起来然后在拘留所关一晚上
that's cuffs and a night in the lockup.
他在威胁我们
He's threatening us.
你得先把我抓起来再说 大块头
You're gonna have to catch me first, lard-ass.
你觉得你能比警车快么 小子？
You think you're faster than a cop car, son?
-没错  -你觉得你能跑那么快？
- Yeah. - You think you're that fast, roadrunner?
没错 我是迈克尔.约翰逊 行么？
Yeah, I'm Michael Johnson, okay?
这世界上最快的人
The fastest man on earth.
你想看我的奖牌么
You wanna see my medals?
他有奖牌 他给你看看
He's got medals.He'll show them to you.
-我可以给你看  -他会证明的
- I can show them to you. - He'll prove it
伙计 你去哪啊？
Dude, where are you going?
拜托
Come on.
你等着 你等着
You just wait. You wait.
再见
Yeah, bye-bye.
棒
Nice.
谁留下的这个怪东西？
Who the fuck left this monstrosity?
-它像是  -特种部队
- It's like some... - Gl Joe.
很沉
It's heavy.
我觉得我们应该把它拿走
I think we should take it.
是的
Yes.
借过
Excuse me.
同志们 我看到一群酒鬼用酒瓶子砸塔
Hey, guys. We got some drunk guys breaking bottles against the tower.
他们不听我的
They're not listening to me.
可能他们会听你们的
Maybe they'll listen to you.
人们尊重警察
People respect the badge.
我觉得我们应该把它带到蓝调之屋
I think we should take it down to the House of Blues
看看能卖多少钱
and see how much we can get for it
好主意
That's a clutch idea.
嘿！离开这！快走！离它远点
Hey! Get away from there. Go on! Get off it.
你们在干什么？
What you all doing?
快走 离开这！
Go on, get outta here!
-嘿 各位 问问... -快走 回家找妈妈去
- Hey, you guys. See if... - Go on. Run home to Mommy.
嘿 问问他们有没有在椅子下面落一个包
Hey, see if they left a backpack under my bench.
亚特兰大911
Atlanta 911.
你能听到么？
Can you understand me?
可以 请讲
Yes, Go ahead.
你们违抗自卫队的命令
You defy the order of the militia
什么？
What?
我又接到了一个奇怪的电话
I got another weird one.
这不是他们的 理查德
Well, it ain't theirs, Richard.
我不喜欢这东西
I don't like this.
我们发现了一个可疑包裹 我们最好上报
We got ourselves a suspicious package. We better call it in.
可能只是某个醉鬼把它落在这了
Probably just somebody run off drunk and forgot they left it.
我仍然觉得我们该上报
I still think we ought to call it in.
把它带到失物招领处吧 理查德
Just take it to lost and found, Richard.
我们是不是该先看看里面有什么？
Shouldn't we unzip it, and see what's inside first?
不不 你不能碰它
No, no, you don't wanna touch that.
你得遵守规则
You got to follow protocol.
这个混蛋非得把它落在你的长椅下 是不是？
Son of a bitch had to get left under your bench, didn't it?
我们发现一个无人认领的背包 请求帮助-
We need assistance on an unclaimed bag-
一个可疑的背包
A suspicious package.
一个在四区的可疑背包
A suspicious package over at section four.
我们还应该围一个环形边界
We ought to set up some kind of a perimeter, too.
-让人们后退  -环形边界？
- Just back away. - Perimeter?
理查德 你疯了么？
Richard, you crazy?
你知道么？我现在宁可疯了也不想出错
You know what? I would rather be crazy than wrong right now.
该死的 理查德 这只是一包啤酒
Shit, Richard. It's just full of beer.
带你到那里
take you there
现在来帮帮我 你们所有人
Yo Somebody help me now, y'all
我会带你去那 毁掉它 毁掉它
I'll take you there Break it down, break it down
同志们 楼下有情况
Hey, guys, there's a situation downstairs.
我们得带你们离开这
We're gonna have to get you outta here.
什么情况？
What kind of situation?
我们正在观察塔前的一个可疑包裹
Well, we're looking at a suspicious package in front of the tower.
已通知执法机关 他们正在现场
Law enforcement is aware and they're on the scene.
如果警察告诉我们得离开 我们就走
Well, if the cops tell us we gotta go, we'll go.
乐队在舞台中间 我们不能直接喊停
The band's in the middle of a set. We can't just shut down.
知道么 如果我再过来
Yeah, you know what, if I have to come back here,
就不能有问题和犹豫了
there's gonna be no questions and no hesitation.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我们发现塔前有一个炸弹
We got a bomb scare in front of the tower.
你们应该知道
You should be aware of that.
华盛顿一直有炸弹威胁 但从来都没出过事儿
We get bomb threats all the time in DC. They're never anything.
你真行 我得撤了
Cool for you. I'm out of here.
有什么发现么？
You got anything?
当地警察昨天就发现了
Local cop discovered yesterday
他实际上是一个波兰体操运动员的远房表弟
he's actually second cousins with a Polish gymnast
这算个故事么？
Is that a story?
别再火上浇油了
Doesn't get me hard.
我也不想
Me, neither.
你看起来不错
You look nice.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
你有打火机么？
Do you have a lighter?
你知道我不抽烟的
You know I don't smoke.
好吧 我去找个打火机 马上回来
All right, I'm gonna go find a lighter. I'll be back.
抽烟会要了你的命的
Those'll kill ya.
怎么死不是死啊
Well, gotta die of something.
希望不是今天
Not today.
西尔弗 里面还有11个人
Silver, still got 11 people inside.
我已经告诉了他们这一切
I made them aware of everything.
我们还没开始撤离
We're not evacuating just yet
听着 你知道这是个假警报
Listen, you know this is a false alarm.
-好么？冷静  -你们在找背包？
- Okay? Calm down. - You gentlemen looking for the package?
-是啊 是什么东西 -跟我来
- Yeah. What have we got? - Follow me.
就在这边儿 不好意思 借过
Right down here. Excuse us, coming through.
借过
Excuse me.
亚特兰大911
Atlanta 911.
世纪公园里有炸弹
There's a bomb in Centennial Park.
什么？
What?
你们有30分钟的时间
You have 30 minutes.
你知道世纪公园的地址吗？
Do you know the address of Centennial Park?
请你们能往前挪一挪
I'm gonna need you to move forward.
借过 各位 借过 请往前挪一挪
Excuse me, folks. Excuse me, if you could move in.
请你们从椅子上下来
I need you boys to get off the bench.
妈 我累了
I'm getting tired, Mom.
-伙计们 请起来 -我也累了
- Guys, get up, please. - Yeah, me, too.
请两位女士从椅子上下来
I need you ladies to move off that bench.
配合我们工作
Come join us.
我们再拍几张就回家
Let's get the last of these pictures and we'll go home.
好
Okay.
这边走
Move this way.
就在那
Right there.
我不知道它在那里多久了
I don't know how long it's been there.
天呐 他们在训练中告诉过我们
Oh, Lord. They told us in training.
看来是真的
It's real.
“看见拆炸弹的人脸色变白 跑就对了”
"You ever see the bomb guy go pale, run.”
袋子里面有三枚管状炸弹 是我见过最大的
We got three pipe bombs in that bag. Biggest I've ever seen.
我们需要马上清空周边100英尺的场地
We need to clear a 100-foot perimeter immediately.
韦尔你有抑爆毯吗？
Vail got a bomb blanket?
安全救援队20分钟内到
The Render-Safe team can be here in 20 minutes.
理查德...
Richard...
我再也不会对你出言不逊了
I'm never giving you shit about anything ever again.
-好了 大家得离开了！-好了 向后退
- All right, we need to move! - All right, back up.
-大家向后退 -请大家马上向后退
- Everybody back now. - Everyone, start moving forward, please!
各位 我们需要大家的帮助 请远离这座塔楼
Everybody, we need you to help us out. Away from the tower, please.
向前走！
Move forward!
伙计们 我们需要你们建立一个防线
Folks, we're gonna need you to help secure a perimeter.
请往前走！马上！
We need you to move forward, please! Right now!
笑一个
Smile.
请往前走
Please, move forward.
请往前走！
Move forward, please!
在后面的人快跟上
These people on the end, ease back.
别停下来
Keep moving.
我眨眼了 再拍一张
I blinked. Take another one.
开始向那边移动 清场
Start moving down that way. Clear out.
左 右 左 右
Left, right, left, right.
请往前走
Move forward, please.
大家都会没事的
Please, everyone's fine.
继续走
Keep moving.
回去 继续向前 注意看路
Go back. Keep moving. Watch your step.
我们现在需要你们的配合 别担心
We need your help right now. Do not worry.
请继续走 女士 别停下来
Keep it moving, please. Ma'am, keep it moving.
谢谢 继续走 谢谢配合
Thank you. Keep it moving. Thank you.
-往这边走 -注意安全
- This way. Come on. - Nice and safe.
注意那边的长椅
Be careful of that bench right there.
嘿！我们得马上离开！
Hey! We've gotta go right now!
有炸弹！得马上离开！
We've got a bomb! Get out right now!
现在就下楼！
Downstairs right now!
继续向前！各位注意脚下 小心点
Keep moving! Everybody, watch where you're stepping, please. Be careful.
借过
Excuse me.
伙计们 我们需要撤离了
Guys, we have got to evacuate!
嘿！听见我说的了吗？
Hey! Are you listening to me?
我们现在要从这座塔楼撤离！有炸弹！立刻马上！
We gotta evacuate the tower! We have a bomb! Right now!
离舞台近一点 抱歉
A little closer to the stage. Sorry.
离塔楼远一点 各位
Just come a little further away from the tower, everybody.
伙计们 我们现在就要撤离 快！
Guys, we gotta go right now. Come on.
有炸弹！现在就得出去！
We got a bomb! You've gotta go now!
你们是怕错过杰克·马克的演唱会吗？
You afraid you're gonna miss the Jack Mack concert?
快 快下楼！
Come on! Get down there right now!
有炸弹！
We got a bomb!
快点 伙计们 快动起来！
Come on, guys. We gotta move!
快 快 快 快 快！
Move, move, move, move, move!
给我飞奔起来 走快点！
Get the lead outta your pants! Come on now!
楼里没人了
Building's all clear.
你得离开这儿了 理查德
You should get out of here, Richard.
-你也是 -去吧
- Yeah, you, too. - Go.
伙计们 离塔楼远一点！
Guys, move away from the tower!
-快 远离塔楼！-整个地方都不能待吗？
- Come on, move away from the tower! - We have to leave the whole area?
发生什么了？
What is happening?
往街上走！到别处去！
Go toward the street! Anything but here!
你们在搞笑吗
Are you kidding me?
快离开！这里有炸弹...
We got to move! There's a bomb...
你们俩还好吗？
You two all right?
还好
Yeah, I think so.
妈
Mom.
快 这边儿 快走
Come on, this way. Let's go.
快 女士
Come on, darli
快离开
Let's go.
你们跑出去
You run out
天呐
Oh, God.
嘿 嘿！
Hey, hey!
嘿 你还好吗？
Hey. You all right?
严重吗？
How bad?
我没事
I'm fine.
-我没事 -好吧
- I'm fine. - All right
你会没事的 兄弟
You're gonna be all right, brother.
救援就在路上 先别动
Help's on the way. Don't move.
能拿点医疗用品过来吗？
Can we get some medical over here, please?
快撤离！很可能有第二个炸弹！
Move them back! There could be a second device!
快走 别停
Let's go. Keep it movi
快走 别停下来
快
Right now.
多人受伤 我们需要救援
Several people down. We need assistance.
我们现在就需要！
We need it right now!
继续走 跟着箭头方向走
Keep moving. Follow these arrows.
妈？
Mom?
A队 发生一起爆炸
A Team, there was an explosion.
派尽可能多的救护车过来
Send as many ambulances as you have.
等会儿 我需要帮助
Hang on. I'm gonna need help.
this is homicide it's ours
this Park estate property that makes it ours
you guys can both get the
fuck out of here this is ATF
actually you can all shut the fuck up
because this is a federal
crime that means it's our jurisdiction
the Federal Bureau of Investigation
you want to help get these injured people
taken care of and keep the perimeter secure
help secure help us
find out who did this
hey mama I guess
I got your message machine
it's Richard him down here a bomb went
off down here but I'm okay
just called to say we when
you get up just turn on TV
I love you
亲爱的上帝
无论是谁干的
请让我们找到真凶
不管他是谁 希望他能有趣一点
And please, whoever he is, let him be fucking interesting.
阿门
Amen.
你是朱维尔吗？
Are you Jewell?
-额 是我 先生  -我是蒂姆·巴克 美国电话电报公司媒体公关
- Uh, yes. Yes, sir. - I'm Tim Barker, AT&T Media Relations.
我听说的是真的吗？你是那个发现炸弹的人？
Did I hear this right? You're the one who discovered the bomb?
是的 先生 是我
Yes, sir, I did.
你知道吗？这使你成为了英雄
That makes you a hero, you know that?
只是做好本职工作而已 先生
I was just doing my job, sir.
你能这么说很好 理查德
That's a nice thing to say, Richard,
但是我收到了很多人的请求 他们想和你谈谈
but we're getting requests from a lot of people who wanna talk to you.
可以吗？
Would that be okay?
美国有线电视网络 凯蒂·库里克 这种的
CNN, Katie Couric, those types.
你上司同意了
Your superior gave the okay.
我得告诉你 有一大批人帮着疏散人员
I gotta tell ya, there were a whole bunch of folks clearing people out.
警方 医护人员 不止是我
Police personnel, medics. It wasn't just me.
你是发现背包的人
You're the one who spotted the package.
人们都想听你说些什么 知道吗？
You're the one people wanna hear from, okay?
要喝点什么吗 需要什么吗？
Can we get you something to drink, take care of you?
那就来杯咖啡吧
I could use a cup of coffee
-如果他们需要我上电视说两句的话 -没问题
- if they're gonna make me speak on TV. - Sure. Absolutely.
我身边这位是理查德·朱维尔
With us now is Richard Jewell,
第一位发现装有炸弹的背包
the security guard who first spotted that knapsack that contained the bomb
并在其爆炸前疏散群众的安保人员
and began clearing people away before it exploded.
-欢迎你 理查德·朱维尔 -谢谢
- Richard Jewell, welcome, - Thank you.
很多人称你为英雄 你也这么觉得吗？
A lot of people are calling you a hero. Do you feel like one?
不 女士 我觉得 额
No, ma'am, I feel like, uh,
我只是做了我应该做的工作
I was a person that did the job that I was supposed to do.
我刚好在对的时间和对的地点
I was in the right place at the right time
并且运用了我在训练中学到的东西
and used my training in the way I was taught
真正的英雄是医护人员和消防员
The real heroes are the paramedics and the firemen,
所有把自己置于炸弹
all the agents that placed themselves
和不愿移动的人们之间的警员们
between the bomb and the people that were refusing to move
因为他们承受了绝大多数的弹片
because they took most of the shrapnel themselves.
做的好 雷达
Good for you, Radar.
你扮演了重要的角色
You played a big role.
你在对的地点 对的时间 做了对的事
You were in the right place at the right time and you did the right thing.
非常感谢
Thank you very much, I really appreciate that
感谢你的到来
Thanks so much for coming in.
谢谢您的邀请
Thank you for having me, I appreciate it
稍后我们将带来更多亚特兰大的资讯
And we'll be back with more from Atlanta right after this.
好孩子
My boy.
找到它
Find it.
就这样 找到它
That's it. Find it.
在这儿 我们找到一个
Right here. We got one.
刚才那个采访感觉怎么样 理查德？
How'd you feel about that one, Richard?
我觉得很顺利 它是...
I think it went well. It was...
每个人都很好 让我觉得自己做了正确的事
Everybody was really nice. Made me feel okay about it.
-是的 你很棒  -干得好 理查德
- Yeah. You were great, - Good job, Richard.
嘿 谢谢
Hey, thank you.
嘿 我想问你们个问题
Hey, I had a question for y'all.
有几个和我一起工作的人昨晚受伤了
I worked with some guys who got injured last night.
格林 西尔弗 米勒
Green, Silver, Miller.
他们能完全康复吗？
You know if they made it out all right?
是的 听说所有的警察都会完全康复
Yeah. Word is all the cops are gonna make a full recovery.
-那太好了 非常感谢  -谢谢你
- That's great. Thank you very much. - Thank you.
理查德 我想让你认识一个人
Richard, there's someone I'd like you to meet.
这是来自伯恩斯坦和克兰公司的布伦纳先生
This is Mr. Brenner from Bernstein and Crane.
你知道这个公司的 他们出版书籍
You know the company, they publish books.
噢 很高兴见到你 先生
Uh, nice to meet you, sir.
你好 理查德 见到你很高兴
Hello, Richard. Pleasure to meet you.
我想和你谈谈你的故事
I would like to talk to you about your story.
你有时间吗
Are you free?
-额...我现在可以走了吗？我可以和他谈谈吗？ -当然 当然
- Uh... Am I free? Can I talk to him? - Sure. Sure.
太好了 我们来喝点咖啡吧
All right. Let's get a cup of coffee.
更好的是 我们可以去吃点东西
Better yet, let's get something to eat.
我完全同意
You're not gonna hear a complaint out of me for that.
我们去吃点好的
Let's get you something good.
不 不 不 我得挂了 我要挂了
No, no, no. I gotta go. I gotta go.
理查德
Richard.
噢 我的天啊
Oh, my Lord.
你出名了
You're everywhere.
我是说 电话刚刚一直在响
I mean, the phone has just been ringing off the hook.
我都需要一个秘书了
I need a secretary.
是的 我想我也需要一个秘书
Yeah, I think I might need a secretary, too.
有个从纽约来的人还问我想不想出书
Some guy from New York just asked me if I wanna write a book.
得了别开玩笑啦
You don't mean it
不 我没有开玩笑
No, I'm not kidding you.
他们告诉我 显然...
They tell me, apparently...
噢 天啊
Oh, Lord.
显然 他们找到了完全符合书中形象的人
Apparently, they got somebody who they think up all the stuff in the book,
他们把东西打印出来然后问你
they type it out and then they just ask you,
“是或否,” "真或假," "它真的发生了吗？" 然后他们付钱给你
"yes or no," "true or false,“ "did it happen?" Then they pay you.
这么做是为了挣钱
You do that for money.
噢 天啊 你就像个摇滚明星
Oh, my God, you're a rock star.
连汤姆·布罗考都在说你的事儿
Tom Brokaw was even talking about you.
我现在都不会思考了
I can't even think right now.
你还好吗？你一直都没睡
Are you all right? You've been up for so long.
-噢 天啊 太糟糕了 -妈妈 抱歉 我都没有拥抱你
- Oh, my God, it was so horrible. - Mama, I'm sorry. I didn't even hug you.
-这太糟糕了 糟糕 -我知道 我就在现场
- It was so awful. Awful. - I know, I was there.
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
谢天谢地你没在那
Be thankful that you weren't there.
-你本打算去那儿的  -我知道
- You could have been there. - I know.
-我控制不了 -是啊
- I couldn't have handled that. - No.
两天前你去那儿看肯尼·罗杰斯
You were there two nights ago for Kenny Rogers.
幸好你昨晚没在那儿
Can you imagine if you were there last night?
我知道 我知道 坐下吧 先坐下
I know. I know. Sit down. Sit down.
你一定很饿 我去给你弄点吃的
You must be really hungry. I'm gonna give you some food.
噢 上帝啊
Oh, my goodness.
噢 妈妈 我跟你说...
Oh, Mama, I'm telling you what...
现场一片混乱 妈妈
It was complete chaos, Mama.
一想到我原本可能请病假
And to think I could've called in sick.
还记得我昨天有多难受吗
Think about how I was feeling yesterday.
-我知道 -我原本可能请病假的
- I know. - I could've called in sick.
我知道
I know.
-然后会发生什么？ -噢 天啊
- Then what? - Oh, my Lord.
肖恩
Shaw.
-不 我得挂了 -你还好吗？
- No, I gotta go. - Doing okay?
不
No.
那枚炸弹在我眼皮底下爆炸了
That bomb went off on my watch.
那是我负责的公园
That's my fucking park.
我们没有足够的警卫监管 是我们的责任
We didn't have enough eyeballs there. That's on us.
让我们抓住那个狗娘养的 好吗？
Let's just catch the son of a bitch, yeah?
好的
Yeah.
我需要你到哈伯沙姆县去
I need you to get out to Habersham County.
这是前副警长的背景
Background on a former sheriffs deputy.
也许和爆炸有关
Might have some connection to the bombing.
是谁？
Who is it?
那个保安
The security guard.
嘿 理查德！
Hey, Richard!
嘿 干得好 伙计
Hey, way to go, man.
我们都为你感到骄傲
You made us all real proud.
谢谢你
Thank you.
克莱尔博士 谢谢你联系联邦调查局
Dr. Cleere, we wanna thank you for contacting the FBI
提出你对理查德·朱维尔的怀疑
regarding your suspicions about Richard Jewell.
我想说清楚 我没有指控他任何事
I want to be clear, I haven't accused him of anything.
我们完全理解
We completely understand.
我只是...
I just...
我看到他获得的关注了
I see the attention he's getting.
这是他在这一直寻求的那种关注
It's the kind of attention he was always seeking here.
骚扰学生 在高速公路拦车
Harassing students, pulling people over on the highway.
都是疯狂的行为
Just crazy behavior.
我想如果我的疑虑无误
And I decided if my fears were correct,
如果他不是人们所认为的英雄
if he actually wasn't the hero they're making him out to be,
而我有与事实相关的信息
and I had information pertinent to the fact,
却没能公诸于众
which I failed to bring to light,
这可能会危及生命
it could jeopardize lives.
好吧 克莱尔博士 你打电话给我们是对的
Well, Dr. Cleere, you did the right thing in calling us.
请放心 我们会跟进这条线索的
We will, rest assured, follow up on this.
你介意我们带走这个文件夹吗？
Do you mind if we take this folder with us?
没问题
Please.
我们将复印一份 然后把原件还给你
We'll make a copy and get you the original back.
为什么该死的ACOG要重新开放那个公园？
Why is the goddamn ACOG reopening that park?
我们什么都没查着！
We don't have shit!
好了 我想知道更多关于朱维尔的事
Okay, I wanna hear more about Jewell.
帕特里克？
Patrick?
没问题
All right.
好吧 当我看到朱维尔这个案子
Well, when I look at Jewell,
我就想到了84年洛杉矶奥运会上的炸弹恐慌案
I think about the bomb scare at the LA Olympics in '84.
把袋子留在公交车上的和发现它的是同一个警察
A bag left on a bus by the same cop who then discovered it
还有今年夏天爱达荷州的火灾
And the fires in Idaho this summer
是一名想要得到扑灭大火荣誉的消防员纵的火
started by a firefighter who wanted the credit for putting them out.
这是一种犯罪侧写
A profile emerges here.
虚假英雄
The false hero.
在采访中 朱维尔对爆炸事件的描述含糊不清
In interviews, Jewell's account of the bombing seems vague
他在讨论受害者的时候看起来很不自在
and he looks uncomfortable discussing the victims.
我还发现他在电视上提到
I also found that his mentioning on TV
说他想回到执法部门 这有点不合时宜
that he wanted to get back into law enforcement a bit inappropriate.
这有很多问题
There's a lot here that's troubli
肖恩探员了解的一切信息
And everything that Agent Shaw has learned about him
都同步在这个档案里了
syncs up with this profile.
你也是这么想的吗 汤姆？
You agree with that, Tom?
是的 长官 我是
Yes, sir, I do.
我们需要监视他
Let's put eyes on him.
-沃森  -怎么了？
- Watson? - Yeah?
-沃森  -在
- Watson? -Yeah.
一号线有电话找你
you have called on line one.
是不是比尔盖茨问我是否需要一百万美元
is it Bill Gates randomly wondering if I need a million dollars so that's an affirmative
如果是的话 答案肯定的
If so, that's an affirmative.
是理查德·朱维尔
It's Richard Jewell.
那个大英雄理查德·朱维尔？
"Richard Jewell" Richard Jewell?
就是大英雄理查德·朱维尔 他在一号线
"Richard Jewell" Richard Jewell, line one.
你好？
Hello?
布莱恩特先生
Mr. Bryant
嘿 抱歉打扰你
Hey, I'm sorry to bother you.
我刚从信息中心拿到你的号码
I just got your number from Information.
希望你还记得我
I hope you remember me.
雷达 叫我沃森 你现在可是全国的英雄
Radar, you can call me Watson. You're a national hero now.
很高兴你打电话来 我们已经没有士力架了
I'm glad you called. We're running out of Snickers,
谢谢你 先生 你还好吗？家里怎么样？
Thank you, sir. How are you? How's your family?
我们都很好 是的 是的
we're all fine, yeah, yeah.
我看你已经不玩儿电子游戏了
I see you've moved up from video games.
是的 对 不是有意为之 但我想是的
Yep. Yeah, I didn't mean to, but I guess I did.
干得好 那是件值得骄傲的事情 我能为你做点什么吗？
Good job. That's a prideful thing. What can I... What can I do you for?
先生 我打电话给你
Sir, I was calling you
因为我想知道 你办过出书协议的合同吗？
because I wanted to know, have you ever done a book deal?
什么 额...为什么问这个？
What, uh... Why?
因为这个爆炸事件 来了一些纽约的家伙
With this whole bomb thing, I got these New York guys
他们想让我写本书
who are asking me to write a book
但我对那一无所知
and I don't really know anything about that.
所以我想打给你 也许你能帮我
So I thought maybe I could call you, you might be able to help me.
当然 听起来和我的专长有点扯不上边
Sure, Sounds a little far-fetched,
但是合同就是合同 但 是的 我们可以谈谈
but contracts are contracts, but, yeah, we could talk.
所以 你不在美国小企业管理局工作了吗？
So, are you not the US Small Business Admin anymore?
因为我最开始试过给那打电话
'Cause I tried there first
没有 我不干了
No, I moved on.
噢 怎么会这样？
Oh. How come?
换种生活方式而已
Lifestyle decision.
你的电话号码是多少?
What's your phone number?
我的电话号码是404…
My phone number is 404...
404...
-194… -194…
- 194... - 194...
-8188  -8188
- 8188. - 8188.
好的  对了  你先不要签任何东西
All right, well, you just don't sign anything
直到我先看到它  我们就从这儿开始谈
until I see it first. We'll start there.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
好的  我不会在任何纸上签字的  我会等你看过
Yeah, I won't put a pen to the page. I'll wait on it.
嘿  谢谢你  先生  多谢你抽出时间帮我
Hey, and thank you, sir. Thank you for your time.
客气什么
You got it
好的 再见
All right, bye.
-保持联系  -好的 先生
- Stay in touch. - Yes, sir.
-好的  -再见
- Okay. - Bye.
不 别这样
No, no.
别这么兴奋
Don't get too excited.
-别这样 -不
- No. - Yes.
不  冷静下来  亲爱的
No. Simmer down there, hot sauce.
比尔·米勒
Well, Bill Miller.
很高兴见到你  好久没见面了
It's nice to see you. It's been a while.
很高兴见到你 波比
It's nice to see you, Bobi.
我们的英雄在哪？
Where's the hero?
哦  他在家  快请进
Oh, he's in here. Come on in.
你觉得炸药量有多少？
What kind of charge you figure it was?
嗯…
Mmm.
我不确定那家伙用的是什么样的炸药
I'm not sure what kind of explosive the guy used.
它可能是黑火药  火柴头里的强力氧化剂
It could have been black powder, match heads,
也许是一些包裹着图钉的氯酸盐之类的
maybe some kind of chlorate packed with nails.
你知道吗  有意思的是 那包炸弹本应向外喷射爆炸  对吗？
You know, the funny thing is the package was supposed to blow out, right?
所以  当那些酒鬼  就那些孩子把背包踢翻
So, when those drunks, those kids knocked it over,
他们救了不少人
they saved a bunch of lives.
因为炸弹本该向人群中爆炸 达到最大伤亡
Because it was supposed to blow out into a crowd for maximum casualties.
但是当孩子们把它踢倒 它就向上爆炸了
But when they knocked it on its back, it blew upward.
大部分炸药炸向了天空
Most of the ordnance going up into the sky.
它是向“上”炸的
It blew up.
所以  总之  你应该找的是某种电池
So, all in all, what you're looking at is some kind of battery,
加上某种计时器  像一个简易的表
and some kind of timing device, like a simple clock.
也许像我手上带的这种腕表
Maybe a wristwatch like I'm wearing.
这取决布置炸弹的人有怎样的技术水平
Depends how high-tech the guy got.
有一些人  特别是一些退役军人
Some of these guys, especially if they're ex-military
或者一些大学的天才
or they're some kind of whiz out of some university,
他们就会用不同炸药进行组合的策略
they're gonna use a combination of different bomb tactics.
其他人就会按照这个做 就像是菜谱一样
Other people are following it like a recipe.
-为了研究炸药他们可能会炸掉一根手指 -是的
- They're probably losing a finger to it - Yeah.
但是也要取决于你讨论的罪犯是谁和制作炸药的是谁
But depends on who you're talking about and who's making the bomb.
嗯…
Well...
我很高兴了解你对这件事的看法
I like getting your opinion on it,
我也确信你对它研究了很多
and I'm sure you've studied it quite a bit.
-谁又知道呢？ -是啊
- Who knows? - Mmm-hmm.
对于那些布置炸弹的人  事情也是如此啊
That's the thing, too, about these bombers.
放炸弹的可能就是你或我
It could have been you or me.
他们那些人  有一些看起来就像普通人
These guys, some of them, look like regular people.
他们中很多都是如此
Lot of them do.
没错
Yeah.
你们压力一定很大吧
Must be a lot of pressure on you guys.
和平常差不多
No more so than usual.
当然  不过是又一起… 谢谢你
Sure, just another... Thank you.
不过是奥运期间美国碰到的又一起平常的致命炸弹袭击
Just your average deadly bombing on US soil during the Olympics.
没什么大不了的
No big deal.
不知道  你们媒体肯定感受到了这件事的热度  对吗？
I don't know, you guys must be feeling the heat, too, huh?
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
美国有线电视网一定会尽全力报道这件事
CNN is going wall-to-wall with this.
这就是我们为什么来这
Is that why we get this
的原因？
outfit?
所以  给我点儿能报道的消息
So, then give me something I can print.
凯西 你知道我不能这样做
Kathy, you know I can't do that.
没关系  我已经知道你们在调查某人
That's all right. I already know the Bureau's looking into somebody.
很好  是什么让你这么想？
Yeah, what makes you think that?
是朋友
Friends.
-朋友? -线人
- Friends? - Sources.
线人?
Sources?
你们调查的到底是谁？
Who is it?
凯西 如果你不能从他们嘴里套到消息
Well, Kathy, if you couldn't fuck it out of them,
你凭什么认为从我这儿能套到
what makes you think you're gonna fuck it outta me?
你知道什么让我烦恼吗  凯茜 那就是人们不了解
You know what bothers me, Kathy, is that people don't understand
我们需要花多大的功夫在这样的案子里
how much work goes into making a case like this.
那简直是不眠不休
It's effort 24/7.
嗯
Hmm.
你说得对
You're right
要不要和我说说？
Why don't you educate me?
我不会让别人把它搞砸的
I will not have this screwed up.
外面已经发生过一次屠杀了
That was a massacre out there.
没有更多的人被杀简直是奇迹
It's a miracle more people weren't killed.
我绝不会报道
I would never go to print
如果没有来自第二方的证实
without independent corroboration from a second source.
而且那会让我们进入一个十分不同的阶段
And that would put us in a very different zone.
你懂的
As you know.
真的?
Really?
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
是什么样的阶段？
What kind of zone?
你要自己去发现
You have to find out
我们在调察那个保安  朱维尔
We're looking at the security guard, Jewell.
-真的? -是的
- No shit? - No shit.
一定要调查发现炸弹的人
You always look at the guy who found the bomb,
就像你一定要调查发现尸体的人
just like you always look at the guy who found the body.
而且这个人  他有不良记录
But this guy, he's got a bad past.
符合英雄-放置炸弹者的犯罪侧写
Fits the profile of the hero-bomber to a T.
就是那个和他妈住在一起的胖混球  当然了
That fat fuck who lives with his mother. Of course.
我怎么没想到这点  我是说 这真是太棒了
How did I miss that? I mean, that is amazing.
哇
Ooh.
你很棒
You are good.
你非常棒
You're very good.
是吗
Yeah.
但这就意味着时间紧迫了
This kind of puts a clock on things, though.
你想要找个房间或者干脆上我的车?
You wanna get a room or just go to my car?
春宵一刻
This is happening.
让我们赶紧离开这里
Let's get the fuck outta here.
-好的 -很好
- Okay. - Yeah.
宝贝  我需要你帮我做点儿修饰文字的事
Sugar, I need you to do one of those better word things you do.
你是说帮你改写文章?
You mean rewrite you?
是的  你知道我的文笔不好  不过这一次的报道比较特殊
Yeah, you know I write like a brick, and this one is kind of special.
是什么？
What is it?
哦 小事 就是 呃
Oh, nothing. It's just that the, uh,
FBI认为理查德.朱维尔是放炸弹的人 正在调查他
the FBI is looking at Richard Jewell as the bomber.
现在你有时间帮我了吗？
Do you have time for me now?
-我的时间任你支配 -很好 那我们开始工作吧
- I got all the time you need. - All right, let's work.
把所有事都告诉我
Tell me everything.
你去哪？
Where you going?
去拿我的笔记
To get my notes.
“最先警告警察在世纪奥林匹克公园
"The security guard who first alerted police to the pipe bomb
有炸弹存在的那名保安
that exploded in Centennial Olympic Park
目前是联邦调查局的调查目标
is the target of the federal investigation into the incident
爆炸导致两人死亡 超百人受伤
that resulted in two deaths and injured more than 100.
理查德.朱维尔  33岁  前执法机关人员
Richard Jewell, 33, a former law enforcement officer
符合独行炸弹客的犯罪侧写
fits the profile of the lone bomber.
这份侧写大致为失意的白人男子
This profile generally includes a frustrated white man
退休警员  或退伍军人
who is a former police officer, member of the military,
或想要从警的人 此人一心想成为英雄
or police wannabe who seeks to become a hero.
随着爆炸的发生
Jewell has become a celebrity in the wake of the bombing,
朱维尔成为名人 并将登上今日秀”
making appearances on The Today Show,"
FBI知道你有这些消息吗?
FBI knows you have this?
哦  是的  我的线人说每个人都知道了
Oh, yeah, My guy says everybody's got it.
网络上有了
Networks have it.
CNN有了
CNN has it.
GBI有个人也是这么说的  局里是在调查朱维尔
Got a guy at GBI says the same thing. Bureau's looking at Jewell.
那为什么没有任何人报导这件事？
Then why isn't anyone reporting it?
没有人感觉到我们被利用了吗
Anybody feel like we're getting worked here?
该死的  约翰  我们负责报道奥运会
God damn, John, these are our Olympics.
如果我们不先发布这则消息  那我们在这做什么？
If we don't lead on this story, what the fuck are we doing here?
行吧
Okay.
去掉下午版的内容  把头版换成这个
Tear up the afternoon edition, and replate the front page.
我们要报道这件事儿
We're running it
谢谢
Thank you.
这里是CNN突发新闻
This is CNN Breaking News,
我们被要求向大家逐字转播这则新闻报道
We've been asked to relay the story to you verbatim, which we'll do.
这是来自《亚特兰大期刊》的引文 “最先警告警察
"The security guard," and this is a quote from The Atlanta Journal,
在世纪奥利匹克公园
"who first alerted police to the pipe bomb
有炸药存在的那名保安
that exploded in Centennial Olympic Park
成为了政府调查的焦点…”
is the focus of the federal investigation..."
现在 让我们来快速回顾一下 我们刚得知了
Now, to recap quickly, we are just getting details
重大进展的一些细节
on what appears to be a major development,.
恭喜
Congratulations.
噢！
Whoo!
耶！
Yeah!
是谁把调查的事泄露给了亚特兰大期刊报？啊？
Who the fuck leaked this investigation to the AJC? Huh?
肖恩！
Shaw!
-长官？  -把朱维尔带来
- Sir? - Get Jewell in here.
进行非对抗性面谈  今天！
Nonconfrontational interview, today!
-你好？  -理查德·朱维尔吗?
- Hello? - Richard Jewell?
是的 我... 我是理查德
Yeah. I'm... I'm Richard.
联邦特别探员丹·贝内特 汤姆·肖恩 有空吗?
Special Agents Dan Bennet, Tom Shaw, FBI. You got a minute?
有 我... 是的 我有空 进来吧
Yeah, I've got... Yeah, I've got a minute. Come on in.
谢谢
Thank you.
夫人
Ma'am.
呃...
Um...
呃 妈妈 这是探员贝内特和肖恩
Um, Mama, this is Agent Bennet and Shaw.
-很高兴见到你 -这是我妈妈 波比
- Nice to meet you. - This is my mother, Bobi.
-你好吗？ - 很高兴见到你 夫人
- How do you do? - Pleasure, ma'am.
我能为你们做点什么?
What can I do for y'all?
我们局正在制作一个训练视频
Well, the Bureau's actually putting together a training video
关于如何处理可疑包裹的 希望你能参加
on how to deal with suspicious packages, and we'd love you to be a part of it.
你觉得怎么样?
How's that sound to you?
乐意效劳 是的 没问题
I would love to help out with that, yeah, absolutely.
你做到了 理查德 你让他们看到了你是怎么做警察的
You did it, Richard. You showed them what kind of cop you can be.
你做到了
Look at this.
是这样 我们今天就要拍
See, the only thing is that we're shooting it today.
所以 你现在就得跟我们去办公室
So, we'd need you to follow us to the field office right now.
因为时间挺紧的 可以吗?
Because time's a little bit tight. Is that okay?
知道吗? 我很愿意去 可我今天还要上班
You know what? I would love to, but I still got to work today.
今天我轮值
I got my shift
呃 不会很久的 理查德
Uh, this won't take long, Richard.
好的 知道吗? 我会去的
Yeah, you know what? I bet we can make that work.
我可以打电话告诉他们晚去一会
I can call in and tell them I'm gonna be a little bit late.
我的意思是 我想帮你们 我也在执法部门
I mean, I want to help you all, and I'm law enforcement, too.
-我们知道 确实如此 - 我们知道
- We know that Yes, indeed. - We know that.
是的
Yeah.
-好吧  -那么 咱们出发吧?
- All right - So, you're all set to go, then, huh?
-好 好  -好极了
- Yep. Yeah. - Great.
-出发吧  -很高兴见到你 夫人
- Let's do it - Lovely to meet you, ma'am.
-非常感谢  -很高兴见到你
- Thank you very much. - Nice to meet you.
-很高兴见到你 -您家很温馨
- Nice to meet you. - Lovely home.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what's going on.
为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
噢 上帝
Oh, goodness.
-朱维尔先生... 联邦调查局来这里做什么?
- Mr. Jewell... - Why are the FBI here?
朱维尔先生 他们对你说了什么?
Mr. Jewell, what have they told you?
他们让你回去工作吗?
Are they letting you go back to work?
呃 是的
Uh, yeah.
他们让你复工了? 你能走了吗?
They're letting you go to work? You're good to go?
是的
Yeah.
联邦调查局正在调查你吗?
Are the FBI investigating you?
我想他们会调查那天晚上公园里的每一个人
I imagine they'll investigate anyone who was at the park that night.
也包括你们所有人
That includes all of you, too.
他们有没有告诉你不能离开市区?
Have they told you yet you can't leave town?
没有
No.
朱维尔先生 你被捕了吗?
Mr. Jewell, are you under arrest?
你可以随意走动吗?
You're free to go wherever you like?
你可以自由出行吗 理查德?
You're free to go wherever you'd like, Richard?
-你为谁工作? -发生了什么事?
- Who are you working with? - What happened out there?
如今人们认为你是头号嫌疑犯
What do you think of the appearance that
你如何看待这种现象?
people are saying that you are now the prime suspect?
这是怎么回事 理查德?
What's going on, Richard?
我不是嫌疑犯
I'm not a suspect.
你为什么跟联邦调查局谈话？
Why are you talking to the FBI?
朱维尔先生 联邦调查局找你做什么?
Mr. Jewell, what does the FBI want with you?
能不能再给我们透露点信息?
Can you give us any more information?
不好意思 那些媒体的人一直跟着我
Sorry, I think I got some media following me.
不 那都是我们的人 我们的人
No. Those are our guys, bud. Those are our guys.
“理查德·朱维尔 33岁 之前在执法部门工作”
"Richard Jewell, 33, a former law enforcement officer,"
文章说 “符合独行炸弹客的犯罪侧写
the story goes on to say, "fits the profile of the lone bomber.
这份侧写大致为失意的白人男子
This profile generally includes a frustrated white man
退休警员 或当过兵
who is a former police officer, member of the military,
或者想要从警的人 此人一心想成为英雄
or police wannabe who seeks to become a hero.
第一个在世纪奥林匹克公园发现管状炸弹
The security guard who first alerted police to the pipe bomb
并报告警方的保安
that exploded in Centennial Olympic Park,"
所以 直到出现明显的异常前
So, up until it obviously went sideways,
那天晚上一切正常 对吗?
everything pretty normal about that evening, right?
是的 我觉得就是一个普通的夜晚
No, it was a regular night from what I could tell.
所有人都玩得很开心
Everyone was having a great time.
就像在庆祝
It was like a celebration.
是的 毫无...
Yeah. No air of...
是的 你玩的很开心
Yeah, you were having fun.
我也玩得很开心 是一段快乐时光
I was having fun. It was a good time.
但是有几个家伙
But there was some guys
带着啤酒罐或者之类的东西？
with beer cans or something like that?
塔楼后面的家伙
Guys behind the tower.
他们在干嘛? 他们在扔...
What were they doing there? They were throwing...
-啤酒瓶 - 啤酒瓶 是的
- Beer bottles. - Beer bottles. Yeah.
他们在打闹 嬉戏
They were horsing around, fooling.
我打断了他们 跟他们讲了一下 他们就离开了
I broke it up and I gave them atalking-to, and they left Yep.
就在塔楼后面吗?
And that was behind the tower?
-是的 长官 - 好的
- Yes, sir. - Right
然后你又回到塔楼附近
then you came back around the tower
在那里你看见了被丢弃的包？
and that's where you saw the package unattended?
-是的 长官 -没错
-Yes, sir. - Right
你看到有人从长椅边离开吗?
And did you see anyone walking away from the bench?
没有 长官 如果看到 我会跟着他的
No, sir. I would've tailed them if I did.
好的
Yeah.
所以 你也不知道是谁把包放在这里的?
So, you have no idea who might have put that package there?
是的 长官
No, sir.
但不管是谁干的 我觉得他们都该被处死
But whoever did, I think they ought to fry.
是的 我们也这么认为 理查德
Yeah. We think so, too, Richard.
必须的
Absolutely.
听好了 我们打算这么做
So, here's what we're gonna do.
为了做到尽量真实
We're trying to be as authentic as possible
这其中包括你是如何对待嫌疑人的
and part of that has to do with how you treat a suspect.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
好吗?所以 我们接下来要假装
All right? So, what we're gonna is we're gonna pretend
把你带入到这个场景中
that we actually brought you in, in that regard.
-可以吗？ - 这...
- Right? - That...
我们向你宣读米兰达警告 你同意放弃这项权利
And we read you your Miranda rights and you've agreed to waive them.
-事实上 你可以签一份表格 - 是的 为什么你不...
- In fact, we have a form you can si - Yeah. Why don't you..
这就再好不过了
This'll be good.
这样看上去就真实了
Just so it looks real.
是的 你在下面签上字
Yeah. So, you just sign on the bottom there
我们把它录下来
and we'll get that on tape
然后我们继续采访
and then we'll continue on with the interview.
可以
Okay.
好的
Yeah.
对不起 理查德 可能我没有说清楚
I'm sorry, Richard, maybe I wasn't clear.
你得真的把名签上
You actually have to physically sign the paper.
这是一份真实的文件
This is a real document.
当然了
Well, of course.
我们是为了确保真实性 理查德
We're going for authenticity here, Richard.
为了保证视频的真实性
It has to be real for the video.
对不起 长官
sorry, sir.
我觉得签这样的文件会让我不舒服
I don't think I would feel comfortable signing something like this.
理查德 我们只是想...
Richard, we just want...
知道吗? 我们为什么不... 为什么不中断一会?
You know what? Why don't we... Why don't we take a quick break?
-下面停止摄像 - 好的
- Go ahead and stop the camera. - Okay.
嗯...
Um...
-是啊 好的 - 我们去聊两句
- Yeah. Okay. - We'll just talk for a second.
-我们马上回来 - 马上
- We'll be right back. - Right back.
我做过副警长
I was a sheriff deputy.
在哈伯沙姆县
Habersham County.
好的 理查德
All right, Richard.
我们要装作什么都没有发生过
We're gonna pretend like none of that ever happened.
咱们换上一盘新带子继续 好吗?
Let's get a new tape going. Okay?
呃...
Um...
现在我们要...
What we're gonna do now...
就这样 我拿到了
There you go. I got it
把它拿出来 扔掉
Get her out there and we'll throw it away.
现在我们要做的是
What we're gonna do now is
探员贝内特会回到这个房间
Agent Bennet's gonna come back in the room,
他会重新介绍自己 向你展示证件
he's gonna reintroduce himself, show you his credentials,
就像一次专业的采访
just like a professional interview.
然后我们会向你真的宣读米兰达警告
And then we're gonna actually read you your Miranda rights.
他为什么要那样?
Why would he do that?
让它更真实 理查德
To make it more authentic, Richard.
我们想让这个看起来尽可能真实
We want this to look as authentic as possible.
进来吧 贝内特探员
Come on in, Agent Bennet.
朱维尔先生…
Mr. Jewell...
我联邦调特别探员丹·贝内特
Special Agent Dan Bennet, FBI.
-抱歉 我觉得…抱歉  -你有权…
- I'm sorry. I think... I'm sorry. - You have the right to...
我需要联系一下我的律师
I think maybe I should contact my attorney.
为什么要这么做 理查德？
Now, why would you wanna do that, Richard?
我意思是…
I mean...
你是一个英雄 对吧？
You're the hero, right?
除非你有什么想告诉我们的
Unless there's something you wanna tell us.
没 我只是
No. But I just
觉得我最好打给他
think I better call him.
好
Okay.
打吧
Here you go.
按九
Press nine.
是的 你好 我想接信息中心找…
Yes, hello, I'm calling Information to get ahold...
一个叫沃森·布莱恩特的人 他是律师
The name is Watson Bryant He's a lawyer.
谢谢 是的 帮我转接
Thank you. Yeah, connect me.
我被转到了他的留言机
I'm getting his message machine.
所以 我打算给他留言
So, I'm gonna leave a message for him.
继续 留言是…
Go ahead. Leave a message and that'll be...
我是…
This...
沃森
This is Watson.
沃森·布莱恩特 我是理查德·朱维尔
Watson Bryant, this is Richard Jewell
打给你是因为 呃
calling in regards to, urn,
有要事要找你 希望你给我回电
something somewhat serious, I would like you to call me back.
我在亚特兰大的联邦调查局办公室
I'm at the FBI office in Atlanta,
不知你能否尽快给我回电话
If you could call me back at your earliest convenience.
谢谢你 再见
Thank you. Bye,
你不能把手机关机 我必须要能联系到你
You can't leave your phone off. I have to be able to reach you.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你想要更多护肤霜吗？
You need more toner?
-他打了三次电话 -谁？谁打的？
- He called three times. - Who? Who called?
谁？理查德
Who? Richard.
三次都是从联邦调查局审讯室打来
Three times from the FBI interrogation room.
好吧 好吧 好吧 冷静 冷静
All right, all right, all right, slow down. Slow down.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
我是这人唯一认识的律师吗？
Am I the only lawyer this guy knows?
没错
Yes.
报纸说……
The paper says...
报纸说局里已经把他绳之以法了
Paper says the Bureau has him dead to rights.
在我那里 当政府说某人有罪时……
Where I come from, when the government says someone's guilty...
……你就知道他们是无辜的
...it's how you know they're innocent.
这里会有不同吗？
It's different here?
我不知道 看起来挺惨的
I don't know. Looks pretty bad.
我不管
I don't care.
明天我们有三四件像这样刺激的案子
We'll get three or four cases as juicy as this tomorrow
而你还有很多其他事要做
and you have so much else to do.
好吧 好吧 帮我跟外地办事处接线 可以吗 纳迪娅？
All right, all right. Connect me with the field office, would you, Nadya?
这就来
Right away.
谢谢
Thank you.
除非你太忙了
Unless you're too busy.
-你没有其他事要做吗？-我没有其他事要做 没有
- Don't you have any work to do? - I have nothing else to do, no.
是的 我是沃森·布莱恩特 理查德·杰维尔的律师
Yes, this is Watson Bryant, attorney for Richard Jewell.
我想跟我的当事人说话 拜托了
I'd like to speak to my client, please.
抱歉 先生 我们这里没有叫这个名字的人
I'm sorry, sir, we have no one here by that name.
是啊 你说的对 的确如此
Yeah, you do, actually.
现在让我和我的当事人通话
Put me on the phone with my client now.
请稍后打来 先生 也许我们能获取更多信息
Please call back later, sir. Maybe we'll have more information.
再拨一次那个号码 好吗？
Dial that number again, would you?
对 我是沃森·布莱恩特 理查德·杰维尔的律师
Yeah, this is Watson Bryant again, attorney for Richard Jewell.
我的下一通电话是打给迈克·华莱士的60分钟电话
My next call is gonna be to Mike Wallace of 60 Minutes
问他为什么联邦调查局矢口否认一个市民
to ask him why the FBI would deny a citizen
获得法律顾问的宪法权利
his constitutional right to legal counsel.
请告诉我你名字的拼法好吗？
Can I have the spelling of your name, please?
有你的电话
Got a call for you.
你好？
Hello?
理查德 我是沃森 你在那做什么？
Richard, it's Watson. What are you doing in there?
他们说他们需要我拍一部训练片
They said they needed me for a training film.
不 他们不需要你来……
No, they don't need you for...
你现在是嫌疑人 你没看报纸吗？
You're a suspect Have you read the newspapers?
你有签什么吗？有供认什么吗？
Have you signed anything? Have you confessed to anything?
没 当然没有 我没有这么做
No, of course not. I didn't do this.
好的 听我说 认认真真听我说
All right, listen to me. Listen to me real carefully.
对任何人闭口不言 你明白我意思吗？
Just don't say anything to anyone. You understand me?
离开那个鬼地方
Get your ass out of there.
让我和负责的探员谈谈
Let me talk to the agent in charge.
他想跟你谈
He wants to talk to you.
我是探员肖
This is Agent Shaw,
审讯结束了 没什么可说的 听见没？
This interrogation's over. Not another word, you hear me?
他一直在全力配合
He's been cooperating fully.
嘿 我口吃了吗？
Hey, did I stutter?
别再审讯了！
No more questions!
-让他离开 听懂没？-行 好吧
- Get his ass out of there, you hear me? - Okay, Well,
祝你愉…
have a nice...
他挂我电话
He hung up on me.
你的律师真牛 恭喜你啊
You have a very loud lawyer. Congratulations.
你被指控了吗？
Were you charged?
你做了吗？你放炸弹了吗？
Did you do it? Did you set that bomb?
理查德 联邦调查局的人说了什么？
Richard, what has the FBI said to
理查德 他们今天跟你说了什么？
Richard, what did they say to you today?
联邦调查局的人跟你说了什么 理查德？
What did the FBI say to you, Richard?
联邦调查局指控你了吗？
Did the FBI charge you?
你安置了那个炸弹吗 理查德？
Did you set that bomb, Richard?
关于联邦调查局的访问你能告诉我们些什么？
What can you tell us about the FBI interview?
理查德 联邦调查局的人跟你说了什么？就跟我们说说吧
Richard, what did the FBI say to you? Just tell us.
我们要联系上韦恩·斯科特有点困难
We are having some trouble connecting to Wayne Scott
我们希望稍后能从他那里得到更多信息
We hope to have more from him later.
他可以给我们提供交通状况的信息
He can update us about the traffic situation,
同时自从世纪公园……
also since Centennial Park is...
他们现在全都跟着我
They're all after me now.
……他可能是我们目前唯一看到公园的人
...he may be our only view of the park for a while.
所以我们会回过头再看 现在我们要把它还给
So we will checking back. Right now we're gonna throw it back to
NBC新闻和汤姆·布罗考
NBC News and Tom Brokaw.
据推测 FBI
The speculation is that the FBI
即将用他们的说法“立案”
is close to "making the case," in their language.
他们很可能有充分证据马上逮捕他
They probably have enough to arrest him right now,
可能有充分理由起诉他
probably enough to prosecute him,
但你总想要有足够的证据来判他有罪
but you always wanna have enough to convict him as well.
这个案子仍有许多漏洞
There are still some holes in this case.
为什么汤姆·布罗考这么说你？
Why did Tom Brokaw say that about you?
那就是汤姆·布罗考
That was Tom Brokaw
与世纪公园爆炸案的最新进展
with the latest update on the Centennial Park bombing.
我们回来时……
When we come back...
我不知道
I don't know.
-嘿 这是谁？-我不认识
- Hey, who's this? - I don't know.
我不认识这个男的是谁 跟我来 我们去采访他
I don't know who this guy is. Come with me. Let's get him.
先生？先生？先生？您是哪位 先生？是理查德的朋友吗？
Sir? Sir? Sir? Sir? Who are you, sir? Are you Richard's friend?
您到这里来看谁？您到这里来看谁？
Who are you here to see? Who are you here to see?
您是理查德的一个朋友吗？
Are you a friend of Richard's?
-为什么您会在这儿？-您是哪位？
- Why are you here? - Who are you?
我是理查德的一个朋友
I'm a friend of Richard's.
您能告诉我们一些内幕消息吗？您有帮他安装那个炸弹吗？
Can you give us some insight? Did you help him set that bomb?
您叫什么？告诉我们一点什么吧？
What's your name? Tell us anything at all.
您是家属吗？
Are you a family member?
我是理查德的一个朋友
I'm a friend of Richard's.
嘿
Hey.
-嘿  -外面真是一团糟
- Hey. - Shit show out there.
你拿到欠我的100美元没？
You got that $100 you owe me?
哦！您一定是妈妈了
Oh! You must be Mom.
您好吗？我是沃森
How are you? I'm Watson.
我很抱歉这个世界陷入了疯狂
I'm so sorry the world has gone insane.
哦 吵死人了
Oh, that's annoying.
我们把电话拿走 好吗？
Let's get rid of that, shall we?
呃……
Uh...
有点像在你耳里钻孔
It's kind of like a drill in your ear.
接下来 你只需要和我谈谈
For the next little while, the only person you need to talk to is me.
他得保持沉默
He does not open his mouth again
就算有警察出现 或是FBI探员
if there's a cop present, or an FBI agent
GBI的人 或是交通管理员
or someone from GBI, or a crossing guard.
明白吗？
Is that clear?
我生来就是要尊重权威 先生
I was raised to respect authority, sir.
小伙子 权威就在窗外想要生吞活剥了你
Son, authority's what's outside that window looking to eat you alive.
来瓶啤酒怎么样？
How about a beer?
-好的 抱歉 我给你拿点东西 -不必说抱歉 谢谢 理查德
- Yeah, sorry. Let me grab you something. - No, no. Thanks, Radar.
好的
Yeah.
我想和你儿子单独在一起
I'm gonna need to be alone with your son.
我不想无礼 但如果有第三者在 那就没办法了
I hate to be rude, but if there's a third party, there's no privilege.
喔
Oh.
是的 第三者 然后他们可以
Yeah, third party, then they can
-反对我们说的所有事情  -没事
- compel anything we say. - No.
很高兴认识你 恕我冒昧 波比 谢谢
Very nice to meet you. Sorry to be rude, Bobi. Thanks.
你参加了什么极端组织吗 理查德
You belong to any extremist groups, Richard?
没有 我讨厌那些东西
No, I hate all that stuff.
任何反政府组织或者
Any anti-government affiliations or...
不
No.
你有朋友与任何边缘组织有联系吗
Any of your friends affiliated with any fringe organizations?
没有
No, no
异教组织呢
Religious cult?
除非成为一名浸礼会教友属于异教徒
Not unless being a Baptist is a religious cult.
美国步枪协会
NRA?
步枪协会是边缘组织吗
N... Is the NRA a fringe group?
你跟3K党成员一起出去玩过吗
You ever hung out with any Ku Klux Klan members?
如果有 那也不是有目的的
If I did, it wouldn't have been on purpose.
关于出书 你联系过其他律师吗
You contacted any other lawyers about this book deal?
没有 只联系了你
No. You're the only one.
理查德 这是死罪
Richard, this is capital crime here.
要判死刑的
This is death penalty.
我可以帮助你 但首先我要知道真相
I can help you, but only if I know the truth.
你做没做
Did you do this?
没有
No.
你是在问我有没有做这事？
Are you asking if I did it?
我问你有没有参与世纪公园爆炸案 是的
I'm asking you if you had any part of the Centennial bombing, yes.
所以 你与这件事有没有关
So, if you had anything to do with this,
有没有参与
had any part in this...
我
I did...
我没有在世纪公园放炸弹
I did not plant that bomb in Centennial Park
我误以为你是知道的
and I made the mistake of assuming you knew that.
是 好吧 让我们把这些混蛋打的屁滚尿流
All right, well, let's beat the hell out of these bastards.
好吗
Okay?
你是他的律师吗
Are you his attorney?
你和理查德·朱维尔是什么关系
What is your relationship with Richard Jewell?
我想如果不调查理查德·朱维尔
I think the FBI would be derelict
联邦调查局就会失职
not to investigate Richard Jewell.
他们只是在做他们该做的工作
They're just doing their jobs.
你什么时候再与他碰面
When are you meeting with him again?
他们只是在做该做的
No, they're just doing their job.
他们只是想确认无风不起浪
They're just making sure no rock is unturned.
你会再与他碰面吗
Are you gonna meet with him again soon?
借过
Excuse me.
是的 我和理查德认识10年了
Yes. I've been friends with Richard for ten years.
-你是他的律师吗  -是的
- Are you his lawyer? - I am.
-他放炸弹了吗  -你是他律师吗
- Did he set that bomb? - You are his lawyer?
-是的  -你叫什么
- Yeah. - What is your name?
你会为他辩护吗
You'll be defending him?
也许会
Possibly.
偷上车不算侵宅 对吗 布莱恩特先生
Not quite real estate law, is it, Mr. Bryant?
哇哦 我的天
Whoa! Jesus Christ!
你是何方神圣
Who the hell are you?
我可以成为你最好的朋友
I could be the best friend you'll ever have.
凯西·斯克鲁格斯 亚特兰大期刊记者
Kathy Scruggs. AJC.
是的 当然
Of course you are.
出去
Get out.
你现在是理查德的实际辩护律师了吗
Have you secured an actual defense attorney for Richard yet?
无可奉告
No comment
-从我车上下去  -瞧瞧 无可奉告帮不了我
- Get out of the car. - See, "no comment" doesn't help me,
也就意味着我帮不了你
whi means I can't help you.
这就是你想做的吗 你想帮我
Is that what you wanna do? You want to help me?
沃森 我不清楚你接这个烫手的山芋是什么感受
Watson, I don't get the sense you grasp the tank that's about to roll over you.
我们现在在谈美国政府
Wa're talking about the US government here
调查恐怖活动嫌疑人
investigating a terrorism suspect.
-你需要我  -好的 听着 疯女人
You need me. - Okay. Listen, crazy lady,
-你需要我  -好的 听着 疯狂的女人
你想要我叫警察吗
you want me to call the cops?
哦 请便
Oh, please do.
我很受警察欢迎 我整天讲他们的故事
The cops love me. I tell their stories all day.
让我讲讲你的
Let me tell yours.
我只是想问几个问题 这有助于我讲你的故事
I'm just gonna ask a couple questions that'll help you tell your story.
-你需要我的帮助  -下车 从我的车里下去
And you need me to help... - Get out. Get out of my...
- 你真有胆量  -是的 我就是这样
You got some balls, man. - Yes, I do.
-下车  -别这样
- Get out. - Come on.
我只是想问几个简单的问题
I'll just ask you a few questions.
-下车   -我们可以同行
Get out. - We can go together.
-来吧 等我拿出笔记本  -从我的车里滚下去
Come on. Til get my notepad. - Get the fuck out of my car now!
滚下车
Get out of my car!
真受够了
I'm sick of this shit.
你知道到哪里可以找到我
You know where to find me.
-是的 别担心  -我从来没有上过电视
Yeah. Don't worry. - Never been on TV before.
没事的
You'll be fine.
朱维尔先生的律师 布莱恩特先生
Mr. Jewell's attorney, Mr. Bryant.
-谢谢你能来  -你太客气了
Thanks for coming in. - You're welcome.
政府那边怎么说
What are the authorities telling you about
-他们怀疑你的当事人吗  -嗯 没什么
their suspicions about your client? - Uh, nothing.
没有深层次沟通
No communication whatsoever?
他们对我说的话就是他们不会去抓他
All they've said to me is that they're not going to arrest him.
这就是他们昨天告诉我的
That's what they told me yesterday.
你信吗
You believe that?
不信
No.
你觉得他们会去抓他
You think they are going to arrest him?
我认为不管他们抓不抓都不会告诉我
I don't think they'd tell me whether they were or they weren't That's all.
你认为联邦调查局对你的当事人跟踪调查
What do you think of the manner in which the FBI has treated your client
-会是什么态度  -我想不管是谁
pursuing this investigation? - I think whoever the bum was
泄露了理查德·朱维尔是调查重点的信息
that leaked that Richard Jewell was the focus of this investigation,
他都应该受到严厉的起诉
he deserves to be prosecuted or dealt with in some serious way.
我认为这个调查
I don't think that this investigation
应该秘密进行 不该暴露
should be conducted under world spotlight, if you will, like this.
关于这个小屋被搜查的事 你的当事人跟你说了什么吗
What's your client told you about this cabin that's being searched today?
据我了解 那是他原来的住处
It's his former residence, as I understand it.
你应该知道一些事情
You need to understand something
从这事发生的第二天起 为了这件事
I have barely had the time to take a breath in this case
我连喘气的时间都没有
since it started the other night.
我们就开始跟媒体和联邦调查局周旋
We have been reacting to the media, to the FBI,
屁股都没落凳子
and I have not sat down
一直忙着对整件事做深入调查
and conducted an in-depth interview about all these things
那些是你们想知道的事
that y'all are asking me about.
那么为什么你这么相信他是无辜的呢
Then why are you so convinced of his innocence?
因为我认识理查德有段时间了
Because I've known Richard for a while.
我看着他的眼睛 问他这个问题
I've looked him in the eye and I've asked him the question.
但是你也承认你都不知道他有个小屋
But you've admitted to me you didn't even know he had a cabin.
你不知道这些事 不知道他之前被捕
You didn't know about this... this prior arrest.
你不知道他曾经犯罪
You didn't know about the prior misdemeanors.
关于他的从前 有太多事情你不知道
There's a whole lot of priors you didn't know about.
我没有对理查德的过去做系统调查
I have not conducted a thorough investigation into Richard's history.
不 我可以理解这一切
No, I understand all that.
我猜到了 我之所以问你的是考虑到你还没有做调查
I guess what I'm asking you is considering that you haven't done that
考虑到有些事情你还不知道
and considering there are things that you didn't know,
你为什么如此确信他是无辜的
why are you so convinced of his innocence?
因为我相信他
Because I believe him.
平白无故
Plain and simple?
是的 没有理由
Yeah. That's right
我对很多人很多事都不了解
I don't know a whole lot of things about a whole lot of people that I know.
我没有理查德的警方记录 你可能有 但我…
I don't have Richard's police records. You may. I don't...
我只是在一些事情上没有跟上节奏 仅此而已
I have not gotten up to speed on some things. That's all.
但只是因为我不知道这些事
But just because I don't know these things
并不意味着我没有觉察到
doesn't mean that I don't have a feel
理查德与这起事件有关
for where I think Richard is in this case.
你记得哈伯沙姆治安部门
Were you aware that the Habersham Sheriffs Department
要他去寻求心理咨询吗
had asked him to seek psychological counseling?
我也不知道
I don't know that either.
但是我知道很多人都应该看心理医生
But I know a lot of people who ought to have psychological counseling.
沃森·布莱恩特 非常感谢
Watson Bryant, thank you very much.
回见 谢谢
See ya Thank you.
1小时22分 我们马上回来
Twenty-two past the hour. We'll be right back.
首先 我们想再次稳住民心
First of all, we wanna reassure the public that
让他们相信尽管发生了昨天的悲剧 亚特兰大仍然是个安全的地方
Atlanta is a safe place in spite of the tragedy of last evening.
你好
Hello?
你因为假扮警察被捕过吗
Were you arrested for impersonating an officer?
是的 有一次
Yeah, once.
-那情况很复杂  -那是……
- It was complicated. - It was...
你打算告诉我吗
Were you planning on telling me?
是的 当然 我只是
Yeah, of course. I just...
昨天有点受惊吓 我忘记告诉你了
In all the hoopla yesterday, I guess I just forgot.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ! What the...
还有别的事情忘记说了吗
Was there anything else that you forgot?
因为我刚刚在今日秀上表现的笨手笨脚
'Cause I just had my ass handed to me on the fucking Today Show!
拜你所赐
Thanks a lot
好消息真多
More great news.
谁会成为冠军 米歇尔 约翰逊 瓦科 还是德克萨斯
The man who would be king, Michael Johnson, Waco, Texas
谁会打破奥运会记录
attempting to do what no man has ever done in Olympic competition,
赢得男子400米和200米冠军
win both the 400 and 200 meters.
出发
Go.
信号枪响了 阿托·博尔顿在最后
Flashbulbs flashing, Ato Boldon away last
这是弗兰克·弗雷德里克斯 迈克尔·约翰逊也追上了
Here's Frank Fredericks, And here comes Michael Johnson,
得走个合适的速度
About the right speed, I guess.
-是？-是.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
他们即将进入直道
They're approaching the top of the straightaway.
迈克尔·约翰一马当先
Michael Johnson reaching deep.
现在计时多少
What are we clocking?
他领先 迈克尔.约翰快要冲刺到终点了
He has the lead, Michael Johnson is closing on the finish!
迈克尔.约翰为金牌而跑！这是奥林匹克的历史
Michael Johnson running for gold! And it's Olympic history!
他打破了他自己的记录
He destroys his own record!
-用时  -六分钟
- Time. - Six minutes.
好吧 我们知道第二次报警是在12点…
Okay, we know the second 911 call was placed at 12...
58分
就是用这儿的公用电话打的
From the pay phone that was right here.
我们也知道理查德在公园里
We also know that Richard was inside the park
在声光塔附近时是12点…
near the sound and light tower at 12...
57分
当比尔·米勒上报可疑背包时
When Bill Miller called the backpack in.
他要走完全程就只有……
He would've had to cover the distance in...
一分钟 所以他不可能做到
One minute. So he couldn't have done it.
有可能骑自行车
Could've ridden a bike, I guess.
一个来回？ 那也不可能
There and back? No.
真的不是他干的
He really didn't do this.
不是他
No.
这家伙要蒙冤入狱了
This kid's getting railroaded.
我们得帮帮他
We're gonna help this guy.
我们得帮他 他快蒙冤入狱了
We're gonna help this guy. This kid's getting railroaded.
我去
Holy...
你不要说话 我来说
You don't talk. I talk.
他们只是来寻查
They're just gonna look around.
这屋子里你有枪吗？
You got any guns in the house?
有 我们可是在乔治亚州
Yeah, we're... we're in Georgia.
是啊 当然 去拿出来
Yeah, of course you do. Go get them.
把它们放到你床上 放在眼皮下 不要有任何隐藏
Lay them on your bed so we can see them. We don't want any surprises.
他们要来多少人
How many of them are coming in here?
呃...
Uh...
要来几个
There... There's a couple.
他们能脱鞋进屋吗？
Can they leave their shoes outside the door?
好 我可以问问他们 波比 我不知道他们是否愿意
Well, I could ask them, Bobi. I don't know if they would oblige.
哦 上帝啊！
Oh, God.
Oh, good Lord.
嗯...
Um...
你在期待丧尸入侵吗？
Were you expecting a zombie invasion or something?
不 我不期待丧尸 我期待鹿 我打猎
No, I wasn't expecting zombies. I expect deer. I hunt.
你打猎？好吧
You hunt? Okay.
雷达 我向你解释一些事情吧
Radar, let me explain something to you.
你现在唯一的罪
All you're guilty of right now
就是让人以为你是安置炸弹的嫌疑人
is looking like the kind of guy who might set off a bomb.
你的所有加固犯罪形象的举动都会把我们逼上绝路
But everything you do that promotes that image is gonna hang us.
抱歉 用词不当
Sorry. Poor choice of words.
外面那些豺狼想把你当成案板上的肉
Those jackals out there, they want your ass on a chopping block.
所以还有任何古怪
I just... Is there anything else odd or quirky
或稀奇的事还有待我发现吗
or fucking weird that I'm gonna discover today?
是 有点
Yeah, kind
我好几年没有交税了
I haven't paid my taxes in about a couple years.
情况越来越好了
This gets better and better.
枪 枪 枪 我讨厌枪
Guns, guns, guns. I hate guns.
每次理查德去打猎 我都说
Every time Richard goes hunting, I say,
你不准把死斑比拖进这里来
"Don't you dare drag a dead Bambi in here.
我不吃斑比肉
I don't wanna eat Bambi."
但你知道什么吗？
But you know what?
理查德 当他是哈伯沙姆县治安官的副手时
Richard, when he was deputy with the Habersham County Sheriffs,
他在射击测试中得了98分
he got 98 out of 100 on his shooting test.
太棒了 嗯-嗯
It was awesome. Mmm-hmm.
了不起
That's great.
好吧
-Okay.
你不要说话 我来说 重复
You don't talk. I talk. Say it.
我不说话
I don't talk.
但我要这些家伙知道这点
But I want those guys to know that
我也是执法人员 就像他们一样
I'm law enforcement, too. Just like them.
听着 就是这点
See, right there?
你说话了 我们要避免这样 好吗
That's talking. That's what we don't want, okay?
你挑了一个好律师 理查德
You picked the right lawyer, Richard.
都准备好了吗
We all set?
-是的 -好吧 我们走 快点
- Yeah. - All right, let's go. Come on.
我们从后面开始
Let's start in the back.
拿进来 快 每个人都按数字号码
Bring it in. Let's go. By the numbers, everybody.
按数字
By the numbers.
跟紧
Hold on.
好的
Okay.
好吧 随你们这些家伙怎么折腾
Yeah, so, you guys go ahead and take everything.
拿毯子也好 想拿啥拿啥 我也是执法人员 我能理解
Take the carpet, whatever you need. I'm law enforcement, too, so I get it
只要明白你拿的东西
Just know that whatever you take,
都能证明我的清白
it's just gonna prove that I didn't do anything.
是 我们以前做过这个
Yeah, we've done this before.
你将成为法律顾问 布莱恩特先生？
You'll be counsel, Mr. Bryant?
计划如此 是的
That's the plan, yeah.
好的 如果你要留下 你得戴上这些
All right, if you're gonna stay here, you're gonna have to put these on.
好 我们走吧 手套和脚套
Yeah, let's go. Gloves and booties.
好
Yeah.
你听到了 要戴脚套和手套
You heard the man. Booties and gloves.
沃森 他们拿走了我的特百惠杯子
Watson, they're taking my Tupperware.
好 我们现在合作一下 迟早会拿回来的
All right, let's play ball right now. We'll get it back.
如果你需要帮找东西 请随时问我们
If y'all need help finding anyth feel free to ask one of us.
我们可以帮忙
We can help.
只是尽量帮忙
Just trying to help.
在那里
It's in there.
你读过那本书吗？
You ever read that book?
那里面有很多关于警察程序的内容
Got a lot in it about police procedure.
很好的一本书 有点争议
It's a good one. It's kind of controversial.
这是一本好书
It's a good book.
我可以帮你那个
I can help you with that.
那是我的带子
I babysit with those.
你知道吗 其实如果你们在外面等着
You know what? Actually, it might be easier
我们工作会更容易一些
if you guys just waited outside while we did our jobs.
-好主意 我们出去吧  -谢谢！
- Good idea Yeah, let's do that - Thank you.
我们出去 理查德 让我们离开这鬼地方
Let's do that, Richard. Let's get the hell out of here.
谢谢配合
Thank you.
约翰逊 罗萨里奥 有发现吗
Johnson, Rosario, anything?
我们之前怎么说的
What was the agreement?
我不说话
That I wouldn't talk.
是 那你怎么做的
Yeah, whafd you do?
我说话了
I talked.
他们没安好心 你懂吗？你知道的 对吗？
They wanna fry you. You understand that? You know that, right?
这里每个人都没安好心
Everyone here wants to fry you.
你就是一块培根肉
You're a little piece of bacon.
好吧 聊点轻松的
Well, on a lighter note,
你从来没有告诉过我你跳槽的公司名字
you never did tell me the name of the firm you moved to and whatnot
我自己开的公司
I opened my own.
什么使你做那样的事情？
What made you do something like that?
公司意味着合伙人 合伙人认为他们可以告诉你是谁
Firms mean partners, and partners think they can tell you who to be.
我不太在乎别人对我的要求
I don't care much for being dictated to.
嘿！你没有权利
Hey! You have no right
-给老娘回来  -妈妈 怎么了
- Come back here. - Mama, what's wrong?
他们搜查了我的内衣裤
They went through my underthings.
他们想让我们受多少侮辱？
How much indignity do they want us to take?
好吧 波比 嘿 等等 伙计们 不好意思
All right, Bobi. Hey, hold on, fellas. Excuse me.
妈妈 嘿...
Mama, hey...
波比 对不起 伙计们
Bobi. Excuse me, fellas.
波比
Bobi.
-打扰一下 -他们从你这里拿走了什么？
- Excuse me. - What did they take from you?
请退后 请退后
Hold on now. Hold on.
波比 让我来
Bobi, let me take care of it for you.
交给我好吗
Can I take care of it for you?
我去拿 抱歉
gonna go get them. Excuse me.
你有什么可以跟我们分享？
What can you share with us?
显然他们找到了一些非常危险的连裤袜
They found some really dangerous pantyhose, apparently.
-是的
-Yeah.
理查德
Richard.
过来一下 我想跟你谈谈
Come here for a sec. I want to talk to you.
-快点进来  -好的 警官
- Come on inside. - Yes, sir.
我能帮什么？
What can I help with?
只要进来一下 一会儿
Just come on inside. Just for a second.
他们从房子里搜出了什么
What did they pull out of the house?
是他做的吗 沃森
Did he do it, Watson?
不 他没有 理查德·朱维尔是无辜的 他是英雄
No, he did not. Richard Jewell is an innocent man. He's a hero.
如果他是无辜的 那为什么联邦调查局在这里？
If he's innocent, then why is the FBI here?
我们欢迎联邦调查局 我们很高兴他们在这里
We welcome the FBI. We're glad they're here.
不 你没有
No, you don't.
你知道这是假的  凯西
You know that's not true, Kathy.
我能看看这些盒子吗？
Can I see those boxes, please?
好 我们接下来要做这些事
All right, here's what we're gonna do.
我把手机给你
I'm gonna hand you this phone,
等手机接通后
and when I do, you're gonna wait till the beep
你就说
and then you're gonna say into it,
“世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟”
"There's a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes."
我...呃...
I'm, uh...
抱歉 为什么
I'm sorry, Why?
我们需要一个声音样本 你说几遍
We need a voice exemplar. Like you to say it a few times.
“世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟”
"There's a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes."
这可能是证明你清白的唯一方法
It might be the only way to clear your name.
我的确想帮你们  我也是个执法者
I do wanna help y'all. I'm law enforcement, too.
好吧  那你肯定知道这是有迹可循的吧？
Well, yeah. Then you should know how evidentiary this is, right?
所以  说“世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟”
So, "There's a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes."
"30分钟"  好吧
"30 minutes." Okay.
-响铃之后？  -对
- After the beep? - Yeah.
世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟
There is a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes.
好  再来一遍  大点声
Okay, one more time. Just a little louder.
世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟
There is a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes.
可以 很好 再来一遍
Okay, that's great. Can you do it one more time?
要不再多说几遍吧  连着说
Maybe let's do a series. We'll do a couple in a row.
好吧
All right.
世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟
There is a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes.
There is a bomb in entennial Park. You have 30 minutes.
世纪公园有一颗炸弹 你有30分钟
There is a bomb in Centennial Park. You have 30 minutes.
世纪公园有一颗炸弹
There is a bomb in Centennial Park.
你他妈开玩笑呢？不  不  你别跟他说话
Are you fucking kidding me? No, no, you don't talk to him.
他们说这是标准流程
It's standard procedure, they said.
狗屁  该死
No, hell it is.
-俄罗斯  -布莱恩特先生  听着
- In Russia. - Mr. Bryant, listen.
你的当事人是自愿的
Your client volunteered this.
胡扯  谁知道你们有没有资格
bullshit. Maybe you can do this. Maybe you can't.
今天不行  走吧  理查德
You're not doing it today. Let's go, Richard.
-我们走  -我答应他们了
- Let's go. - I told them I'm doing it
他们没准能证明我的清白
if it helps clear my name.
-我们走！今天不行  -你的当事人同意了
- Let's go! Not today. - Your client agreed to this.
我要起诉你这个混...
I'm gonna sue your ass...
-故意剥夺他的...  -好吧
- for intentional violation... - Okay.
-宪法权利  -好吧
- ...of his constitutional rights. - Okay.
我什么都不管了  你们就是一帮混蛋
I'm having all this shit excluded. You guys are full of shit
走吧
Let's go.
我们能搞定
We got it.
噢  天
Oh, God.
晚安
Have a good night.
他们为什么连吸尘器都要拿走
What do they want with the vacuum cleaner?
好了  这里完事了
All right We're done here.
理查德？
Richard?
我没事  嗯  没事
I'm fine. Yeah, I'm fine.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你进去吧
Let's get you inside.
大卫  你能给她拿点儿喝的么？
Dave, can you get her something to drink?
-拿点儿水？  -好的  没问题
- Maybe some water? - Yeah. Sure.
怎么了
What's going on?
没事
It's nothing.
我挺好
I'm fine.
他们把我的特百惠杯子都拿走了
They took all my Tupperware.
他们要我那些杯子干什么？
What would they need with my Tupperware?
炸弹袭击者用杯子装的钉子
The bomber used Tupperware to hold the nails.
拿走也是正常的
That's standard.
好吧  这跟你有什么关系？
Well, what does that have to do with you?
他们还拿了我照顾孩子的带子  还有迪士尼电影
And they took my babysitting tapes. My Disney movies.
嗯  我认为他们想看看
Yeah, I think they did that because they wanted to see
我们是不是碰巧录到了什么
if we mighfve recorded something on the tapes
比如政治言论之类的
like a political statement or something.
你为什么要替这些人说话？
Why do you keep defending these people?
我没有  我就解释解释
I'm not defending. I'm just explaining.
够了  闭嘴！
Well, stop it!
-嘿 她来了 嘿  -嗨
- Hey, there she is. Hey. - Hi.
-你怎么样  -你好
- How you doi - Hello.
这是  呃...  纳迪娅  她是  呃...
This is, uh... This is Nadya She is, uh...
她告诉我要做什么
She tells me what to do.
来  我来拿  你可真好
Here. Let me take that. That's very nice of you.
我想你们也许想吃晚餐
I thought you might want some dinner.
你真好
Bless your heart.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - Of course.
嗨 我是理查德
Hi, I'm... I'm Richard.
我怎么跟你说的  理查德？
What did I tell you about talking, Rich?
噢
Oh.
噢 天 好吧  看来我再也不能说话了
Oh, God, yeah. I guess I can't talk anymore.
出来吧 理查德 你躲得了初一 躲不过十五
Come on, Richard, you can't hide anymore.
-理查德  一个问题  就一个  -是你做的吗？
- Richard, one question. That's all. - Did you do it?
理查德  你造了多少炸弹？
Richard, how many bombs have you made?
联邦调查局从你家拿了什么  理查德？
What did the FBI take out of your house, Richard?
好的
Yeah.
手榴弹？
Hand grenade?
-你要个手榴弹做什么？  -对  它是空的
- What do you got a hand grenade for? - Yeah, it's hollowed out
只是个镇纸  我在军备品店买的
It's a paperweight. I bought it from a military surplus store.
-好吧  -没有杀伤力
- Yeah. - But it's nothi
天啊  你当然是买的
Christ, of course you did.
长椅上的木片？
Piece of the bench?
...碎片  这是做什么用的？  那是什么？
Splintered piece of... What does that mean? What is that?
对  我从犯罪现场拿了一块长椅碎片
Yeah, I took a small piece of the bench from the crime scene.
-从发生爆炸的地方？  -这是纪念品  留念
- From where the bomb was? - It's a souvenir. A memento.
你为什么这么做？
What'd you do that for?
我觉得我做得很好  那晚值得纪念
I think it was a pretty memorable night where I did something pretty great.
所以  我觉得那块碎片值得保存
So, I thought maybe that was worth holding on to.
哇  好吧
Wow. Okay.
很好
Nice.
-嘿  -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
他们想要你的头发  还有掌纹
They want your hair now, and your palm prints.
真是好时候
Good times.
进来
Come in.
拔了25根  采集25根
我告诉你  你也许有权利这么做
I tell you, you might have a warrant for this,
但你要是这么对我  先打赢我吧
but if you were to do this to me, you'd have to fight me.
你得打屎我才行
You'd have to beat the shit out of me!
你真不像律师啊  顾问
Not very lawyerly of you, counselor.
是  好吧...
Yeah, well...
咱们能在我妈回家前搞定吗？
Can we just get this over with before my mama comes back?
我不想让她看见
I'd like her not to see this.
告诉我 理查德
Tell me, Richard,
你还为你是执法人而骄傲吗？
you still proud to be law enforcement?
你知道吗 要是我工作再努力些
You know what? Maybe if I did my job a little better,
把群众疏散得足够远
and got people far enough away,
那我现在就不用坐在这里了
then I wouldn't be sitting here right now.
是啊  他真是个魔鬼  小伙子  你们想办法吧
Yeah, he's a real monster. Boy, you guys nailed it.
你们有计算过现场到公共电话的时间距离吗
Have you dummies done the math yet on the call from the pay phone?
嘿 你听着 去他妈的公共电话 行不
Hey, listen, fuck the pay phone! Okay?
我的委托人是那晚公园里的人
My clients were the people in the park that night
他们不该被炸得脑浆遍地
that didn't deserve to get their fucking heads blown off.
你知道  我的确对你们的遭遇很遗憾
You know, I actually feel sorry for you guys.
等真正的投弹手故伎重施
When the real bomber does it again,
人们质疑“联邦调查局”在哪的时候
and the country asks, "Where was the FBI?"
你们会说“我们正忙着采集理查德·朱维尔的头发样本”
You're gonna say, "We were busy getting hair samples from Richard Jewell."
-我弄完了  -全都好了？真棒
- I'm done here. - All set? Great
哦  挺好
Oh, good.
那个  理查德  非常感谢你的专业配合
Well, Richard, thank you very much for your professional consideration.
你知道  警察不为难警察
You know, cop to cop.
”我们是联邦调查局“
"We're the FBI."
我看着你警察不为难警察呢  就在这
I got your cop to cop. Right here.
-呵呵  -门在那
- Uh-huh. - There's the door.
找到了 谢谢
Found it Thank you.
理查德  我们对待这些蠢蛋
Richard, we need to be a little less
要少操心  多正义
solicitous and a little more righteous with these assjacks.
我说 只是头发 会长回来的  没事
I mean, it's just hairs. They'll grow back. It's fine.
你说什么？
Whafd you say?
不过是头发  会长出来的
They're just hairs. They'll grow back.
不过是头发  嘿！
They're just hair. Hey!
这破事怎么没让你像我一样气急败坏
Why doesn't this shit make you as angry as it makes me?
我生气啊
I am angry.
你耍我吧
You could have fooled me.
你生气？
You're angry?
我当然生气
'Course I am.
我不知道用“生气”足不足以形容我的感受
I don't know if "angry" is even a big enough word for how I feel.
-拜托  -那就别像个擦鞋垫一样
- Come on. - Then stop being such a doormat.
别再老帮他们说话
Stop trying to be their best friend.
你知道  他们在外边笑话你呢
You know, they're making fun of you out there.
-你知道他们怎么说你的吗？  -我知道！
- You know what they're calling you? - I know that!
我明白他说"警察不为难警察"是什么意思
I know what it means when he says "cop to cop."
他不是真的说“警察不为难警察”
He doesn't mean cop to cop.
-他觉得我是面团宝宝  -是吗 我差点就信了
- He thinks I'm the Pillsbury Doughboy. - Do you? Could have fooled me.
我还以为你们要订婚了
I thought you guys were gonna get engaged.
嘿！理查德！现在去吃块饼干吧
Hey! Richard! You go for a cookie right now,
我要把你的双手剁下来塞进你屁股里！
I'm gonna chop off your hands and shove them up your ass!
那就吃块饼干呀 混蛋
Try eating a cookie then, fucker.
你为啥要成为我的代理律师？
Why'd you wanna represent me and be my lawyer?
嘿 你好像需要帮助
Hey, you looked like you needed some help.
你好像需要通过出书事务挣点钱
You look like you might've needed money from a book deal.
呃 我想问你 你为啥选择我呢？
Well, let me ask you, why'd you pick me?
电话簿里有许多律师 为啥你偏偏选择我？
There's a lot of lawyers in the phone book. Whafd you pick me for?
我选你是因为你是唯一
I picked you because you were the only one
在“美国小商业管理局”工作的律师
at the US Small Business Admin bureau
而且你没有把我当成一个五岁小孩 没有叫我
who didn't treat me like a five-year-old, and call me,
“零食狂” 也没有叫我“死胖子”
"bag of snacks" and "blimp,"
“米其林怪”以及“面团宝宝”
"Michelin Man/1 and "Pillsbury Doughboy."
只有你把我当成一个人
You're the only one who treated me like a human being!
但现在你吼了我 要求我变成一个我不会成为的人
And now you're just yelling at me, telling me to be somebody that I'm not!
我不知道要怎样成为这样一个人
I don't know how to be that guy!
你就是这样一个人！我是我自己！
You're that guy! I'm me!
怎么了
What?
我不知道你说啥
I don't know what you're talking about.
我们办公室和这屋子被监听了
噢 天呐
Oh, my Lord.
他们怎么可以做这种事？
How can they do that?
很简单 因为你很好糊弄
easy because you don't matter.
这就是为什么
That's how come.
我们必须离开
We need to go!
走啊！
Move!
你们必须离开
You guys gotta
我们要撤了
We need to evacuate!
达奇斯先生
Mr. Dutchess.
有空吗
You got a minute?
我来付
I got that.
给
There you go.
-我能先把东西吃完吗？-不行
- Can I finish my food? - Nope.
呃 好吧
Mmm. That's good.
他们已经认为
They've decided that since
既然你不可能亲自打911电话
you can't have placed the 911 call yourself
那你一定有个同伙
that you must've had a partner.
他们觉得你的同伙一定是你的男朋友
They think your partner must be your homosexual boyfriend,
他们觉得那个人可能就是我
which they decided is probably me.
啥？
What?
他们让我带窃听装置
They asked me to wear a wire.
我告诉他们我不需要 我说你曾是一个英雄
I told them to shove it. I said you were a hero.
而他们说 “好吧 要是他真的是个英雄
And they said, "Well, if he really is a hero,
那么他就不需要紧张兮兮 你也不需要 ”
then he's got nothing to worry about and neither do you."
他们还说 呃 你的一个GBI伙计
They also told me that, uh, one of your GBI buddies
就是他来看你的时候 你给做了面条的那个伙计
you know, the one you made lasagna for when he came over...
我知道 米勒嘛
Yeah, Miller.
对
Yeah.
是的
他也带了窃听装置
He was wearing a wire, too.
他对你揪着不放
He's got a lot on you.
还有个事儿
There's, one other thing.
他们还问我有没有试过土质铁管炸弹
They asked me if I'd ever had any experience with pipe bombs
我必须告诉他们事实
and I had to tell them the truth.
你知道 这种小炸弹
You know, the little ones.
我们以前把它丢进地鼠洞里 那时我还是个住在维吉尼亚州西部的小孩
We used to drop them down gopher holes when I was a kid in West Virginia
大卫…天呐
David... Lord.
我告诉他们这件事在我认识理查德以前已经过去好几年了
I told them this was years before I even met Richard.
我告诉他们好多次了
I told them a couple times.
然而…
Still...
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系
It's okay. Yeah.
好吧
Yep.
没事
It's okay.
我做过…
I did what was...
嘿 关…
Hey, turn...
天呐！你在干啥？
Come on! What are you doing?
我们不能看炸弹爆炸的电影
We can't be watching movies with bombs and explosions
因为此时他们在监听
when they're listening.
拜托…
Come...
你们都…
Y'all...
我只是不想出差错
I'm... I'm trying to do the right thing.
对吗？
Right?
各位…他们难道没有监听吗？
Guys... Are they not listening?
嘿 妈妈 对不起
Hey, Mama, I'm sorry.
妈妈 对不起
Mama, I'm sorry.
拜托别这样？
Please?
妈妈 出来吧 你想看啥 我们就看啥
Mama, come on out. We can watch whatever you wanna watch.
我不管
I don't mind.
妈妈 拜托 我…
Mama, please, I...
我不会再多嘴了
I won't say nothing about anything.
出来吧
Just come on out.
妈妈 对不起 我…
Mama, I'm sorry. I'm...
拜托了？
Please?
妈妈 拜托？
Mama, please?
知道了
I know.
我好害怕 理查德
I'm scared, Richard.
我在这陪着你
I'm right there with you.
没事的
It's all right.
我不知道怎样保护你不受这些人的伤害
I don't know how to protect you from these people.
嘿 你知道吗 你不需要保护我
Hey, you know... You know what? You don't have to protect me.
我才是负责保护的人 我才是
I do the protecting. I do.
好吧
Yep.
来吧 出来吧
Come on. Come on out
你坐下 你想看啥就看啥
You just sit down. You watch whatever you wanna watch.
我不管
I don't care.
对不起 我朝你吼了
And I'm sorry I yelled.
对 她有过三天为儿子自豪的日子
Yeah, she's had about three days to be proud of her son
然后他们就夺走了她的骄傲
and then taken away from her.
对 这样做是不对的
Yep. That ain't right
对不起 理查德
sorry, Richard.
嘿
Hey.
你准备好反击了吗？
You ready to start fighting back?
嗯
Yeah.
理查德
Richard!
你是来自首的吗
Are you here to turn yourself in?
不知道为啥我们不能把这种事留给FBI来做
Don't see why we can't just let the FBI do this.
你能信任他们所作出的结果吗？
You trust them with the results?
你状态很好 别紧张
You're in good hands here. Just breathe.
理查德 是谁让你测谎的？
Richard, whose idea was it for you to take a polygraph test?
沃森
Watson's.
你觉得你的测谎结果会怎样
How do you think you'll do on it?
很好
Fine.
你知道是谁在奥林匹克公园放置炸弹的吗？
Do you know who put that bomb in Olympic Park?
不 我不知道谁在世纪公园放了炸弹
No, I do not know who planted the bomb in Centennial Park.
嘿 我们最好谈谈-
Hey, maybe we better talk-
不 他通过了测谎测试
Nah. He passed.
最高分通过的 没检测到他说谎
Highest level. No deception indicated.
噢 天呐
Oh, Jesus Christ
天呐
my God.
谢谢 伙计 嘿
Thanks, man. Hey.
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿 看看你 哈？
Hey. Look at you, huh?
你成功了 伙计
You did it, man.
-对啊 我们成功了  -你成功了
- Yeah, we did it - You did it.
我们必须要坚信
We must be firm in this.
我们不能被恐怖行为吓倒
We cannot be intimidated by acts of terror.
我要感谢这位勇敢的保安
I want to thank the brave security personnel.
女性60多岁的时候可卡因的用量高涨
Cocaine use is up from women in their 60s.
噢 是吗？
Oh, yeah?
-是啊 看看这个  -祝他们好运
- Yeah. Look at that. - Lucky them.
天呐 那是朱维尔
Holy shit, it's Jewell.
这是凯西.斯格鲁格斯吗？
Is that Kathy Scruggs?
嘿
Hey.
这就是藏在幕后的感觉吗？
Is this what it's like behind the curtain?
-理查德.朱维尔  -你好
- Richard Jewell here. - Hello.
我们就快要求撤回报道了
We're just about to go demand a retraction.
然后去吃汉堡包 你要不要一起？
Then we're gonna go get a hamburger. You wanna come?
-是这样吗  -是啊
- Is that right? - Yeah.
这就像评分最高的科幻片
This is, like, top-rate science fiction.
《炸弹嫌疑人希望引人注目》
"Bomb suspect sought limelight."
你在开玩笑吗？你他妈算老几啊？
Are you kidding me? Who the hell do you think you are?
布莱恩特先生 我做的就是报道事实
Mr. Bryant, what I do is I report the facts.
-你误导公众 这是你做的  -我报道事实
- You lead the public, is what you do. - I report the facts.
-事实？-对 报道事实是我的工作
- The facts? - That's right That's what I do.
-你这个无知 傲慢 充满野心的…  -啥？啥？
- You ignorant, arrogant, ambitious... - Excuse me? Excuse me?
这工作你怎么弄来的
How did you get this job?
-我怎么弄来的工作？  -对啊
- How'd I get this job? - Yeah.
布莱恩特先生 如果你有问题 你可以去找联邦调查局处理
Mr. Bryant, if you have an issue, you can take it up with the FBI
-去调查你的当事人  -哦 得了吧
- for investigating your client. - Oh, bullshit.
这和我无关 不是吗
It has nothing to do with me. All right?
我做的就是听到事实 再报道出来
What I do is, I hear the facts, I report them.
-这是我的职责  -这些事实吗 那真相呢
- That is my responsibility. - The facts? What about the truth?
我的原则是事实至上
My guiding principle is to report the facts.
什么见鬼的原则
What fucking principles?
对我来说原则这种东西是不顶用的
This isn't a principle standing next to me.
去你妈的原则 这个男的名字是理查德·朱维尔
Fuck your principle. This man's name is Richard Jewell.
-他是个英雄 他救了好多人 -你可真是满嘴跑火车
- He's a hero. He saved lives. - You're unbelievable
-到这来胡闹  -难道我是个骗子吗
- just coming in here. - I'm unbelievable?
你知道你酿下多大的错吗
Do you have any idea what kind of wildfire you started?
你毁了他的生活
You've ruined this man's life.
-你或许应该向他道歉  -听着……
- Maybe you owe him an apology. - Listen...
怎么样
How about that?
-朱维尔先生  -你知道 你说啥
- Mr. Jewell... - You know, you are a... What?
我说对于您和您母亲的遭遇我很同情
I said I'm sorry for what you and your mother have gone through.
你简直是垃圾记者中的战斗机
You are a miserable excuse for a journalist.
你就是个寄生虫
You're a parasite.
为了卖报 你啥都做得出来 你知道吗？
Anything to sell a goddamn paper, you know that?
那你咋还不上医院呢
Why don't you go chase another ambulance?
去你的
Kiss my ass.
他快不受控了
He's out of order.
都回去工作 这里没什么好看的
Vail can go back to work. There's nothing really to watch here.
继续忙你们的
You can just keep doing your jobs.
不是他做的
He didn't do it.
哦 靠
Oh, fuck.
你特么真不要脸
You got a lot of fucking nerve sitting here.
朱维尔不可能打电话
Jewell couldn't have made the call.
时间距离不对
The math is wrong.
我去走了一遍
I covered the distance from the site to the phones.
他不可能及时来回
There's no way he would have made it in time.
是的 我们知道
Yeah, we know.
你们知道？
You know?
他有帮凶
He had an accomplice.
帮凶？
An accomplice?
是啊 为什么不呢
Sure. Why not?
那关于炸弹的档案呢
What about the lone bomber profile?
警察？帮凶？
The wannabe cop? With an accomplice?
首先 档案只是一个出发点
Well, first of all, profiles are always just a jumping-off point.
如果你记得的话 俄克拉荷马城就有两名投弹者
Oklahoma City had two bombers, if you remember.
所以 到底是谁干了这件事？究竟是谁呢
Okay, so who did it? Who is it?
好像你上次害了我之后我还会告诉你似的
Like I'm gonna tell you after the way you burned me.
好吧 我就只写针对朱维尔的案件进展开始舒缓
Fine. I'll just write that the case against Jewell is starting to weaken.
证据不足等等 看情况说吧
Bad facts, et cetera. See how that goes.
你知道吗？我不确定你是从哪里想到这个主意的
You know what? I'm not sure where you get this idea
我为你想出来的 或者是我们一起
that I work for you, or that we work together.
我甚至都不知道为什么我要和你说话
I don't even know why I'm fucking talking to you.
我知道为什么 因为我们彼此相互依存
I know why. And you need me just as much as I need you.
你知道的 甜心
You know what, sweetheart?
我一点都不需要你
I don't need you a goddamn bit.
再来一杯 谢谢
Can I have one more, please?
在我身旁的是波比·朱维尔
Next to me is Bobi Jewell,
理查德·朱维尔的母亲
mother of Richard Jewell.
造化弄人
By some savage twist of fate,
理查德·朱维尔被错误无理地指控犯有谋杀和故意伤害罪
Richard Jewell has been wrongfully and falsely accused of murder and mayhem.
她儿子的控告方是最有权势的两股力量
Her son's accusers are two of the most powerful forces in the world today.
美国政府和美国媒体
The United States government and the media.
过去的四周里 这些可怖的势力勾结
For the past four weeks, these horrific forces have combined
令她处在水深火热之中
to make her daily existence a living hell.
就在我说话之时 他们还在继续压榨她
As I speak, they continue to crush the very life out of her
压榨她唯一的儿子
and her only son.
下面我将介绍芭芭拉·朱维尔
I introduce Barbara Jewell,
世纪公园爆炸案的第113名受害者
the 113th victim of the Centennial bombing.
我的名字是芭芭拉·朱维尔
My name is Barbara Jewell.
我受雇于当地一家保险公司 担任索赔协调员
I am employed as a claims coordinator with a local insurance agency
我在那里工作了13年了
and I have worked there for 13 years.
大约在四周之前
Approximately four weeks ago,
超过100个人受伤
over 100 people were injured
两人死亡
and two people lost their lives
这是奥林匹克公园爆炸案的惨剧
as a result of the Olympic Park bombing.
我非常担心那些受害者和他们的家庭
My heart goes out to these victims and their families.
我感到筋疲力尽
I am so very drained.
我向天祈祷 希望大家不会再遇此磨难
I hope and pray to God that nobody ever has to go through this again.
我想你们没有人
I do not think any of you can even
能想象我们生活的现状
begin to imagine what our lives are like.
媒体把我儿子描绘成
The media has portrayed my son
一个犯罪分子
as the person who has committed this crime.
他们窥探我们的隐私
They have taken all privacy from us.
打破了我们生活的宁静
They have taken all peace.
他们窥探记录我们的一切
They watch and photograph everything we do.
就像这媒体
Like the media,
联邦调查局盯着他的一举一动
the FBI follows his every move
不断监视着我们家
and watches my home constantly.
这是为什么
And why?
我的儿子
My son...
我的儿子是无辜的
My son is innocent.
理查德不是在奥林匹克公园放炸弹的人
Richard is not the Olympic Park bomber.
理查德不是凶手
Richard is not a murderer.
他救了人命
He saved people's lives.
总统先生 请听听我的心声 帮帮我吧
Please hear me, Mr. President, and help me.
你有能力来结束这场噩梦
You have the power to end this nightmare.
我的儿子是个英雄
My son is a hero.
我想联邦调查局直到现在才明白这件事
I think the FBI knows that by now.
如果他们不再控诉我的儿子
If they do not intend to charge my son,
请告诉我们
please tell us.
请大声告诉世界
Please tell the world.
总统先生...
Mr. President...
请还我儿子的清白
Please clear my son’s name.
你做的很棒
You did good.
理查德
Richard.
妈妈
Oh, Mama.
非常感谢你做的这些
Oh, thank you for doing that.
噢 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
抱歉 对不起我哭了
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I cried.
我并不想哭的
I didn't mean to cry.
不 真的很不错 真的很棒
No, you did real good. You did better than good.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
让他们瞧瞧你是谁
Let's go show them who you are.
我的天哪
Oh, God.
万幸总算是结束了
I'm so glad that's over.
你做的不错
You did good.
行了
All right.
先生们 请坐
Gentlemen, please have a seat.
我们马上就来
We'll be right with you.
行吧 我告诉你怎么弄
All right, let me tell you how it's gonna go.
他们会要求先见我 定一些规则
They're gonna ask to see me first, set the ground rules.
我想确保他们知道我不是同性恋
I wanna make sure they know I'm not gay.
理查德 我认为我们要更重要的事儿要说
Richard, I think we got bigger fish to fry,
但是你仍有机会告诉他们这个
but you'll get the chance to tell them that.
我确定
I'm sure.
肖恩探员
Agent Shaw.
你敢不敢去看他有没有士力架
Dare you to see if he's got any Snickers.
有点饿了
Kind of hungry.
你知道基本规则是什么吧 雷达
You know what a 1001 is, Radar?
是的先生 对联邦探员撒谎
Yes, sir. It's lying to a federal agent
这是重罪
It's a felony.
如果你谎话连篇
You say anything in there that isn't true,
他们不用证明你是个炸弹手就可以把你关进监狱
they can put you in jail without ever proving you're a bomber.
嗨
Hey.
不知道说什么就保持沉默
You don't know what to say, you say nothing.
你要求五分钟的休息时间 来和我商量一下
You ask for a five-minute break, you consult with me.
你不能即兴发挥
You do not improvise.
明白了吗
You got that?
明白
Yes, sir.
所以 如果你不知道说什么 你该怎么做
So if you don't know what to say, what do you do?
-我就啥也不说  -没错
- I don't say a damn thi - That's right
布莱恩特先生
Mr. Bryant?
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
我只是随便看看
I was taking a look.
你们准备怎么办？
How do you guys wanna handle this?
我们提问 你们回答
We're gonna ask you some questions, and you're gonna give us some answers.
这怎么样
How's that sound?
好的
Okay.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
我去叫他来
I'll go get him.
嗨 你准备好了吗
Hey, you ready, boyo?
是的
Yeah.
应该好了
I think so. Yeah.
不 你要完全准备好
No, I mean ready.
你们不是探员和犯人的关系进行谈话 而是警察对警察
Look at these guys not as suspect to agent, but as cop to cop.
别过分尊重他们
Don't give them any more deference than they're due.
-也别总叫他们“警官”  -好
- And don't keep calling them "sir." - Yeah, well,
但他们可是美国政府啊
they're still the United States government.
不 他们可不是美国政府
No, they aren't the United States government
他们只是三个为美国政府工作的混蛋
They're just three pricks who work for the United States government
明白这区别吗？
You understand the difference?
这个房间里没人能比得上你
Nobody in that room is a better man than you.
明白吗？
You understand?
来吧
Come on.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
就这儿 坐这儿
That's it Sit right there.
这儿？
Right here?
对
Yeah.
感谢你配合我们调查
Thank you for joining us.
朱维尔先生 我们有一些问题想问你
Uh, Mr. Jewell, we've got a few questions
是关于1996年7月27日发生的事
regarding the events of July 27th, 1996,
你可能知道
as you probably know.
具体来说就是世纪公园发生的爆炸案
Specifically the bombing in Centennial Park.
朱维尔先生 你是否
Mr. Jewell, you ever find yourself
登陆过一个名为糖果宝贝的糖果乐园的网站
accessing an Internet site called Candyman's Candyland
浏览过无政府主义者食谱的内容？
regarding the contents of The Anarchist Cookbook?
不 我没有
No, I have not.
但你确实接受过处理爆炸物的警务训练对吗？
But you do have police training in handling explosives?
已问已答 不得追问
Asked and answered.
你有收集世纪公园建筑上的
Did you ever collect any pieces of pipe
任何碎片吗？
from the construction of Centennial Park?
不 我没有
No, I did not.
你有跟在公园的任何人说过
Do you remember telling anybody at the park,
“快给我拍张照吧 因为我马上就要出名了”这句话吗？
"Take my picture now, because pretty soon I'm gonna be famous"?
没有
No, sir.
真的吗？
Really?
你确定吗？
You sure about that?
百分百确定
那么你有说过
How about, did you say,
“我正在去亚特兰大的路上 外面肯定会一团糟”这句话吗？
"I'm on my way to Atlanta It's gonna be a mess out there"?
我是指交通堵塞
I was referring to the traffic jams.
朱维尔先生
Mr. Jewell,
为什么你特别要求要在声光塔舞台那儿站岗？
why specifically did you want to be stationed at that sound and light tower?
我只是喜欢听音乐
I just liked listening to the music
而且 在前一天晚上 我带我妈妈去了
and, the night before, I got to bring my mama down.
我们想听肯尼.罗杰斯表演
We got to listen to Kenny Rogers.
她很喜欢 歌很棒
She liked that. That was nice.
而且我还有个很老套的理由
And I guess I also get a nice vantage point
我想看美女
to take a look at all the pretty girls.
我不是同性恋
I am not a homosexual.
大卫.达奇斯也不是
And neither is David Dutchess.
所以你和大卫.达奇斯不是一对儿？
So you and David Dutchess are not lovers?
已问已答 不得追问
Asked and answered.
朱维尔先生 你说过
Mr. Jewell, you said before
在你从舞台到声光塔
that in your comings and goings back and forth
来来回回的过程中
from the stage to the tower
你记不清具体时间了 对吗？
that you couldn't get an exact fix on the time. Is that correct?
对 但当你想上厕所的时候
Yes, but when you have the runs,
我也确实上了 抱歉
which I did, excuse me,
你不会去注意时间
you're not thinking about what time it is.
你只是想
You're just trying to
横冲直撞到厕所 知道吗？
crab-walk to a bathroom, you know?
所以你不记得
So you don't remember the exact time
你看见醉鬼们往塔上扔瓶子的具体时间？
that you saw the drunks throwing the beer cans against the tower?
对吗？
Right?
没错
No.
你不记得第一次看见背包的具体时间？
You don't remember the exact time you first saw the backpack?
没错
That's correct.
你以前见过那样的背包吗 朱维尔先生？
You ever seen a backpack like that before, Mr. Jewell?
我应该见过
Yeah, I suppose so. Yeah.
你见过那个背包吗 朱维尔先生？
You ever see that specific backpack before, Mr. Jewell?
已问已答 不得追问
Asked and answered.
我们能往下进行吗？
Can we move on?
朱维尔先生...
Mr. Jewell...
你有和大卫.达奇斯或其他同谋
Did you conspire with David Dutchess or anybody else
在世纪公园放置炸弹吗？
to plant a bomb in Centennial Park?
没有
No.
那你是怎么知道在塔的另一头
Then how the fuck did you know to be on the other side of that AT&T tower
是可以躲避爆炸攻击的？
where you knew you'd be protected from the blast?
一颗炸弹正好就在你站岗的地方爆炸
A bomb went off right where you were stationed.
搞得一片混乱 人们倒在地上
Chaos erupts. Bodies hit the ground.
警察被炸飞 妈的 我就是其中一个
Cops go flying. Hell, I was one of them.
你却毫发无伤
You come out without a goddamn scratch.
这是怎么回事儿 理查德？
How does that happen, Richard?
我能问你们一个问题吗？
Can I ask all you fellas a question?
天啊 什么问题？
Jesus. What?
你要指控我犯了什么罪吗？
Do you have any kind of case against me?
我是指证据
I mean evidence.
就像是 在我妈妈的特百惠里发现了任何蛛丝马迹？
Like, any traces of anything on my mama's Tupperware?
或在她的公寓里发现了任何制造炸弹的材料？
Or did you find any bomb-making materials in her apartment?
你有发现任何  -嘿 嘿 嘿
did you find some- - Hey, hey. Hey.
理查德 我们不需要主动-
Richard, we don't need to volunteer-
如果我还要回答其他的 我必须先把这些话说了
I'm gonna say this if I'm gonna say anything.
我走进来 看到你们窗户上的圆形图案
I walk in here and I look at the circle decal on your windows there,
然后我就想...
and I'm thinking...
我曾经以为联邦执法部门
I... I used to think that federal law enforcement
是一个人渴求的最高使命了吧
was just about the highest calling a person could aspire to.
但我不确定现在是否还这么想 你知道吗？
And I'm not sure I think that anymore, you know?
特别是这一切发生之后
Not after all this.
那天晚上我只是尽了职责
I did my job that night,
也因此让一些人幸免遇难
and some people are alive because of that.
你觉得下次安保人员
Do you think that the next time some security guard
再看到可疑包裹时
sees a suspicious package,
他或她还会上报吗？
that he or she's gonna call it in?
我不觉得
I doubt it.
你知道吗？因为他们会看着它然后想
You know? 'Cause they're gonna look at that and they're gonna think,
“我可不想成为下一个理查德.朱维尔...
"I don't wanna be another Richard Jewell...
所以我还是赶紧跑吧”
So I'm just gonna run."
这怎么能保人安全呢
How's that make anybody any safer?
你们可以继续咬着我不放
Y'all can keep following me around some more
做你们现在做的 我能忍受
doing what you're doing. I can stand it.
但是我知道 你们在我身上浪费的每一秒
But I just know that every second you spend on me
本可以花在寻找真正的凶手上
is time that you're not spending on the real guy who did it,
就像沃森说的...
and it's like Watson said...
要是他...
What happens when he...
要是他又作案了该怎么办？
What happens when he does it again?
所以 你有任何证据来指控我吗？
So, do you have anything you wanna charge me with?
你有证据吗？
Can you?
好吧...
Well...
我觉得我们该走了
I think it's time to go.
怎么样？
How'd he do?
他表现的好极了
He did great.
天啊
God.
是啊
Yeah.
太好了
Go on.
自调查起第88天
嘿
Hey.
先生们
Gentlemen.
肖探员
Agent Shaw.
有东西给你们
Got something for yall
什么东西？
What's this?
求婚书
Marriage proposal.
哦
Oh.
幸运日啊
My lucky day.
好吧
Okay.
这是个好的开始
Well, this is a good start.
新闻发布会是什么时候？我想你会
When's the press conference? I'm assuming you'll be
向所有媒体宣布 向汤姆.布鲁考和其他新闻主播宣布
announcing to all the news outlets, Tom Brokaw and the like.
布莱恩特先生 让我把话说清楚
Mr. Bryant, let me be perfectly clear.
我仍然认为你的当事人有罪
I still think your client is guilty as hell.
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
行吧 你有权拥有自己的想法
Well, you're entitled to your opinion.
“兹通知你方 根据证据...”
"This is to advise you that based on the evidence..."
结束了
It's over.
这...
Is...
真的结束了吗 还是这只是他们的另一个手段？
Is it really over or is this just another one of their things?
你赢了 这件事结束了
You won. It's over.
你做得很好
You did good.
我想见..我想见我妈妈
I wanna see... I wanna see Mama.
你想见妈妈？
You wanna see Mama?
是啊
Yeah.
好啊没问题
We can do that.
真的吗？
That's real?
上面是这么写的
That's what it says.
“...在1996年7月27日世纪公园
"...not considered a target in the federal criminal investigation
爆炸案的联邦刑事调查中
of the bombing of July 27th, 1996,
已从调查目标排除”
Centennial Park."
嘿
Hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You got it.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
六年后
你好 沃森·布莱恩特
Hello, Watson Bryant
嘿
Hey.
有什么能效劳的
What can I do you for?
你怎么样？额...
How are you? How's, uh...
天呐 娜迪娅怎么样？
My God, how's Nadya?
他们抓到他了 理查德
They found him, Richard.
抓到谁了？
Found who?
埃里克·鲁道夫
Eric Rudolph.
他供认在世纪公园放置炸弹
He confessed to the bombing at Centennial Park.
你知道他什么时候会被提审吗？
You know when he's being arraigned?
我不知道
I don't know.
-你能帮我查一下吗？ -好
- Can you find out for me? - Yeah.
看看你
Look at you.
理查德·朱维尔于2007年因心脏病去世 享年44岁
沃森·布莱恩特与纳迪娅喜结连理 并育有两子
波比·朱维尔每周六晚都去看望他们
新浪微博@摆渡字幕组 译制
关注微博 掌握最新字幕资源
字幕组翻译/APP开发志愿者 招募中 报名QQ群：377256405